<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golf on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/golf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golf on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/golf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>19th Hole Golf Scorer 3.1</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2016/19th-hole-golf-scorer-3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/19th-hole-golf-scorer-3.1/</guid>
      <description>One of the problems with using 19th Hole on the Apple Watch is making the app show every time you raise your wrist. My solution to this was to go into Settings (either on my iPhone through the Watch app, or directly on the watch) and change it to &amp;ldquo;Resume Last Activity&amp;rdquo; on wrist raise. This worked fine but as I usually prefer the watch face to show on wrist raise, I had to keep setting and re-setting this which was a pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using 19th Hole on the Apple Watch</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/using-19th-hole-on-the-apple-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/using-19th-hole-on-the-apple-watch/</guid>
      <description>19th Hole for iPhone and Apple Watch version 3 is now available through the iTunes App Store. This version is a complete re-write to accommodate the changes in iOS 9 and watchOS2.
The major changes are to do with the way the iPhone and the Watch communicate. In watchOS1, all the brains of the app had to live in the iPhone, meaning that every single interaction on the Watch had to be referred back to the iPhone for processing and the result sent back to the Watch for display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch App - Rejected, then Accepted</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/apple-watch-rejected-then-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/apple-watch-rejected-then-accepted/</guid>
      <description>As described in a previous post, about 9 days ago I submitted my first Apple Watch app for review. The app was an extension of my golf scoring app: The 19th Hole.
I expected that App Store review times would go up dramatically once Apple had allowed developers to submit watch apps, but this proved to be incorrect. Three days after submission, the app was marked as &amp;ldquo;In Review&amp;rdquo;. This seemed to happen last thing on a Saturday, so there was no further action for two days, at which point the app was rejected, with the following details (sic):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Apple Watch App</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/my-first-apple-watch-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/my-first-apple-watch-app/</guid>
      <description>I have just submitted my first Apple Watch app to the iTunes App Store. This is a scary thing to do, since I have never seen, touched or used an Apple Watch and all I had to go on was the Simulator that Apple supplies with Xcode.
At the moment, Apple has only made a limited set of Apple Watch features available to developers, and all Apple Watch apps come tethered to an iOS app - presumably this will mainly be iPhone apps, but I wonder will we be able to connect Apple Watches to iPads?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>