<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>man reader on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/man-reader/</link>
    <description>Recent content in man reader on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/man-reader/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<title>Another Man Reader Update...</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/another-man-reader-update/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/another-man-reader-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A quick update to &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; to version 1.8 is now available through the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for this version was that Man Reader was not previously
detecting man pages installed by third-party IDEs in the Applications folder.
There was also an issue with Man Reader failing to display the text of the
previously selected man page on app launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More complete search for man pages, including in third-party IDEs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for glitch when displaying previously selected page on launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader Update</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-update/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; has just been updated to version 1.7 and is available through
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for this update was to make the app work well with macOS Sierra,
as I found that version 1.6 was sometimes crashing on launch. While doing this,
the update was rejected by the App Store reviewers because it crashed on OS X
10.10. Since I no longer have a Mac running 10.10, I decided to set the minimum
supported system version to OS X 10.11. If you need support for older versions,
you should still be able to download version 1.6 which will work back to 10.7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity to fix some graphical issues, dealing with different
color schemes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The man page list now shows alternating colors even when not using the default
scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When scrolling the man pages past the top or the bottom with a non-white
background, you should no longer see white blocks top &amp;amp; bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader updated to 1.6</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-updated-to-1.6/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-updated-to-1.6/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;Man Reader has been updated to version 1.6 with the permissions needed for
finding all available man pages and a fix for search terms being over-written
after a background update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader 1.6&lt;/a&gt; is now available through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-log&#34;&gt;Change Log:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permissions fix when searching for available man pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed error with new search term being over-written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sand-boxed version now works just as well as the non-sand-boxed so please
switch back to this version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version fixes a problem with sand-boxing permissions potentially not
allowing access to all the installed man pages on your system. This should now
be fixed but if you discover any man pages that are available through Terminal
but not through Man Read, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=Man%20Reader%20not%20detecting%20some%20man%20pages&#34;&gt;email me the details&lt;/a&gt; and help me make Man
Reader better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an issue with a previous search being restored after a background
update, even if a new search term had been entered. This has been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you previously had downloaded the Man Reader (no SB) version of the app from
this site, please revert to the App Store version which you would have needed to
have bought in order to use the downloaded app. If you bought the app from
Paddle, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=Man%20Reader%20transfer%20to%20App%20Store&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; and I will transfer you to the App Store version.
Neither of these other versions will be supported or updated any more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader 1.5</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-1.5/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/man-reader-1.5/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;Man Reader has been updated to version 1.5 with a major improvement in the way
it looks for available man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader 1.5&lt;/a&gt; is now available through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-log&#34;&gt;Change Log:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much improved searching for available man pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sand-boxed version now works just as well as the non-sand-boxed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main feature of this version is that it solves the previous problems with
the App Store version and sand-boxing. This was restricting the number of man
pages listed in Man Reader so I had to release a non-sand-boxed version of the
app to allow for full functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I discovered that although this gave better results, it was still
missing a lot of man pages. Version 1.5 now queries the man page files in a
completely different way which is listing many more man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you previously had downloaded the Man Reader (no SB) version of the app from
this site, please revert to the App Store version which you would have needed to
have bought in order to use the downloaded app. If you bought the app from
Paddle, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=Man%20Reader%20transfer%20to%20App%20Store&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; and I will transfer you to the App Store version.
Neither of these other versions will be supported or updated any more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader 1.4 Now Available</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2014/man-reader-1-4-now-available/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2014/man-reader-1-4-now-available/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader 1.4&lt;/a&gt; is now available through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-new-features-and-fixes-are&#34;&gt;The new features and fixes are:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for plain text view not wrapping correctly for odd-sized fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for HTML text view over-riding font colors that may be invisible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for missing entry (e.g. g++) no longer requires Enter or Return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better automatic selection of matching entries while searching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for animation warning message appearing in Console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status display shows when man page list is being updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searching inside a page now allows a minimum of 2 characters (was 3), so
flags&lt;br /&gt;
e.g. ‘-b’ do not need to be escaped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed path for Network Utility in tool bar (moved in OS X 10.9).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More information available about the effects of sand-boxing for this app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader (no SB)</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2013/man-reader-no-sb/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2013/man-reader-no-sb/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;These instructions are no longer valid. As of version 1.5, the App Store version
of Man Reader has solved the sand-boxing issues and is now as powerful as the
non-sand-boxed version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The non-sand-boxed version will no longer be supported or updated, so please
revert to the App Store version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that Man Reader is not working well for you due to Apple&amp;rsquo;s
sandboxing restrictions, then you can download a non-sandboxed version here. To
find out more about this, including how to test if you are affected, read the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader-sandbox/&#34;&gt;Sand-Boxing Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The non-sandboxed version will only work if you have the App Store version of
Man Reader already installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB)&amp;rsquo; for the first time, it will check to see if
you have a valid installation of &amp;lsquo;Man Reader&amp;rsquo; that you have purchased from the
App Store.&lt;br /&gt;
If you do not, &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB)&amp;rsquo; will offer to take you to the App Store and then
quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already own the App Store version of Man Reader and &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB)&amp;rsquo;
has started once, you can delete the App Store version and &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB)&amp;rsquo;
will keep working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB)&amp;rsquo;, click the download link below. This will
download &amp;lsquo;ManReader-noSB.zip&amp;rsquo;. Double-click on this file to un-zip it, and then
move the &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no SB).app&amp;rsquo; into your Applications folder and use as
normal. Do not delete the App Store version of Man Reader until &amp;lsquo;Man Reader (no
SB)&amp;rsquo; has been run at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;del-download-man-reader-no-sb-del-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Download Man Reader (no SB)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out today (thanks Ron) that under OS X 10.10.3 the security settings no
longer allow the downloaded version of Man Reader (no SB) to run, despite the
fact that I have signed it with my Apple Developer ID. OS X gives a very
un-helpful dialog reporting that the app is damaged. In fact the app is fine,
but being blocked by the security settings. The solution as shown at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tech-recipes.com/rx/45404/mac-downloaded-app-is-damaged-and-cant-be-opened-error-solved/&#34;&gt;TechRecipes&lt;/a&gt; is to change your security system preferences to allow
downloaded apps from anywhere. You only need to do this temporarily as after you
have run the app once you can set this setting back to whatever you had before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Sand-Boxing Man Reader</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2013/sand-boxing-man-reader/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2013/sand-boxing-man-reader/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;These instructions are no longer valid. As of version 1.5, the App Store version
of Man Reader has solved the sand-boxing issues and is now as powerful as the
non-sand-boxed version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The non-sand-boxed version will no longer be supported or updated, so please
revert to the App Store version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all apps in the App Store, &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; is restricted by Apple&amp;rsquo;s
sand-boxing policy. Sand-boxing is a great thing. It isolates apps from each
other and from the system, making it far less likely that a problem app will
cause wide-spread havoc. However for an app like Man Reader, this can lead to a
drop in functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the permissions limitations of sand-boxing, Man Reader can only search
defined paths on your system drive e.g. /usr/, /opt/&lt;br /&gt;
This is where the default man pages are all stored, but if you install other software
(Xcode is a good example), then Man Reader may not be able to list all the available
man pages on your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tell if Man Reader is missing man pages, copy &amp;amp; paste the following command
into the Terminal app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;whatis . &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/Desktop/whatis.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man Reader runs this command internally when it starts, but the Terminal app is
not sand-boxed and so can access everything.&lt;br /&gt;
Running this command will create a text file on your desktop with a list of all available
man pages on your system. Open it in a text editor that can show the number of lines
in a file. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barebones.com/products/textwrangler/&#34;&gt;TextWrangler from Bare Bones Software&lt;/a&gt; is a good free editor that
will do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check what man pages ManReader can read, go to Finder and select &amp;lsquo;Go to
Folder&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; from the Go menu. Paste in the following path:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/Library/Containers/net.troz.Man-Reader/Data/Library/Application Support/Man Reader/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see two files: open the one called &amp;lsquo;ManReader.raw&amp;rsquo; in your text editor.
This is the result of Man Reader running the whatis command. Compare the number
of lines in the two files. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about the order of the items in the file
as that may vary, you are only concerned with the total number of lines in each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be one or two lines more in the whatis.txt file but if there is a big
difference, then you are being sand-boxed&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;
As an example, on my system, the whatis.txt file contains 8954 lines and the ManReader.raw
file contains 2320 lines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;If you are affected by this or think that you might be, I now have a
solution - actually two possible solutions:&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;If you have already bought Man Reader from the App Store, then you can
&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;download a non-sandboxed version&lt;/a&gt;. This will only work if you have the App
Store version of the app installed.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;If you do not already own a copy of Man Reader, and want to buy it
un-sandboxed, then you can now &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;buy it directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=Man%20Reader%20and%20Sand-Boxing&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if you have any issues with this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader 1.1 Released</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2012/man-reader-1-1-released/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/man-reader-1-1-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The update of &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34; title=&#34;Man Reader&#34;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; to version 1.1 has just become available through
the Mac App Store. This update has a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/#new_features&#34;&gt;new features&lt;/a&gt; - thanks to
everyone who made suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As detailed in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/sandboxing-and-the-mac-app-store/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, there have been major issues getting this
app approved with Apple&amp;rsquo;s new sand-boxing restrictions fully in place. But to
their credit, the Apple reviewers have been unfailing helpful and polite in
answering my questions and keeping me informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone finds the new features useful. Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=Man%20Reader&#34;&gt;keep the suggestions
coming in&lt;/a&gt; to make this app even better!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Sandboxing and the Mac App Store</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2012/sandboxing-and-the-mac-app-store/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/sandboxing-and-the-mac-app-store/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As of June 2012, all apps submitted to the Mac App Store have to be sandboxed
i.e. they have to be able to run in a limited environment where they cannot
interfere with other apps or other parts of the system. While this is generally
a good thing, there are problems when apps have legitimate reasons for requiring
access to other resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One annoyance for developers is that Apple&amp;rsquo;s apps are mostly not sandboxed. To
check what apps you have installed that are sandboxed, open up Activity Monitor
(in Applications/Utilities). In the View menu, check that Sandbox is checked in
the Columns submenu. Then you can sort by clicking on the Sandbox title and work
out which apps are already sandboxed. Mail, Preview and Text Edit are now
sandboxed and so is the new Reminders app, but as far as I can tell, no other
Apple apps are. This causes two problems: firstly it is not fair to other
developers if Apple is enforcing a standard which only they are allowed to
break. Secondly, if Apple developers had to follow the same rules as everyone
else, then maybe the system would evolve to become more usable for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Apple developer documentation about sandboxing, there is a section headed
&amp;ldquo;Determine Whether Your App Is Suitable for Sandboxing&amp;rdquo;. Here they list numerous
reasons why any app might not work in the sandbox. But the Mac App Store now
makes sandboxing compulsory, so what to do with apps that are not suitable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some resources can be requested when building the app: access to various folders
(Pictures, Music, Downloads etc), access to Address Book and Calendar data,
printing facilities, networking etc. Beyond the specified list of entitlements
that can be requested, developers can also apply for &amp;ldquo;temporary entitlements&amp;rdquo;
which, if granted, will unlock access to other parts of the operating system.
However these are subject to the whims of app reviewers and will be re-assessed
with every update. Apple has also made it clear that they are intended as a
transition feature and will not be available for ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has lead to a recent spate of popular apps leaving the App Store.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/2012/07/26/mac-app-store-future&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marco
Arment&lt;/a&gt; has discussed this problem with an emphasis on the issue of lack of
confidence in buying from the App Store. If you cannot be sure that an app you
buy will remain in the App Store, then you are less likely to buy it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have run into direct issues with sandboxing already. With
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.picapod.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pic-a-POD&lt;/a&gt;, I used to have
links to the Desktop and Screen Saver panes in System Preferences. These used
AppleScripts which required a temporary entitlement to send an AppleEvent. The
app was rejected because of this, so I had to modify this feature - it now just
takes you to the relevant section of System Prefs, but not directly to either
Desktop or Screen Saver. However Pic-a-POD&amp;rsquo;s help, which runs in Apple&amp;rsquo;s Help
Viewer app, contains exactly the same AppleScripts and so is allowed to access
these preference panes directly. Try working out the logic of that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more serious problems with
&lt;a title=&#34;Man Reader&#34; href=&#34;https://troz.net/manreader/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt;. Man
Reader displays a list of the man pages on your system. Depending on the tools
you have installed, these pages may be in a variety of locations. The shell
command that detects them first reads a config file and then checks the folders
listed in that config file. All it needs is read-only access. With the first
sandboxed version, I asked for a temporary entitlement to give me read-only
access to the startup disk. This was granted, but I have since been informed
that all requested entitlements were granted before the App Store cut-off date.
This may have been meant to be helpful, but it was not useful to allow access
that would later be removed without any warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current version of Man Reader waiting for approval asks for read-only access
to the config file directly and then to every folder listed in that config file.
If approved, this should be able to access all the man pages on a system. I have
no idea whether these entitlements will be granted, but if not, then I will have
to remove Man Reader from the App Store. It would be wrong to continue to sell
an app that only functioned in a limited manner, even though the App Store is
far and away my best form of marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do I suggest Apple does? I think they need to allow apps that are not
sand-boxed. However these apps could come with a warning before installation. In
Mountain Lion, the new security feature called Gatekeeper allows you to specify
the level of security you want when installing apps. Currently the options are
to allow apps downloaded from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac App Store and identified developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They could split the first option in two and allow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac App Store sandboxed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac App Store any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One further wrinkle is iCloud. Apple is encouraging users and developers towards
iCloud data storage and sharing. But only apps in the App Store are allowed to
use iCloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it will be interesting to see how this plays out. Obviously Apple is not
going to care if a tiny developer like me leaves the App Store, but if enough
high-profile developers leave, then there will surely be some consideration
given to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Man Reader update coming soon</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2012/man-reader-update-coming-soon/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/man-reader-update-coming-soon/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Man Reader launched on the Mac App Store a couple of days ago and yesterday I
got an email from a purchaser who reported that Man Reader was not displaying
the man pages for MacPorts, even though he had the paths set up correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed MacPorts to check this out and ran into the same problem. Running
the command &amp;ldquo;man port&amp;rdquo; in Terminal worked fine, but &amp;ldquo;port&amp;rdquo; did not appear in Man
Reader&amp;rsquo;s list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man Reader uses the &amp;ldquo;apropos&amp;rdquo; command to list all available man pages, so I
tested it next. When I found that it was not listing &amp;ldquo;port&amp;rdquo; either, I thought I
had discovered the problem. OS X offers two commands for searching for man
pages: apropos &amp;amp; whatis. The database files used by these commands are updated
weekly by one of the periodic system commands. I manually ran this update
command using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo /etc/periodic/weekly/320.whatis
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This did part of the job, as the apropos command when used in Terminal now
contained the MacPorts man pages. However Man Reader still did not show these
man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reverting to the Console log, I found that this was a sand-boxing problem. The
Mac OS X sand-box was preventing access to the man.conf file (which tells where
to look for man pages), and the whatis database file containing the new data. I
assume that without access to these files, the default locations for man pages
were still searched, but no non-standard locations were being searched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just submitted an update to the App Store that still uses sand-boxing but
requests temporary read-only access to the file system to read these files. If
Apple rejects this, then I will release a version without sand-boxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, you can be assured that the matter is being dealt with and the next
update, whether sand-boxed or not, will allow access to all man pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>