<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Screen Saver on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/screen-saver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Screen Saver on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/screen-saver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to Time In Words screen saver</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/update-to-time-in-words-screen-saver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/update-to-time-in-words-screen-saver/</guid>
      <description>Time In Words screen saver has just been updated to version 1.1 and is now fully compatible with Mountain Lion. It is free to use and can be downloaded here.
The basic screen saver worked before, but searching for an alternative time zone would crash System Preferences. That is now fixed.
The screen saver also shows a thumbnail image when in Mountain Lion and is code-signed with my developer ID for compatibility with Mountain Lion&amp;rsquo;s Gatekeeper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Mac Screen Saver</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/making-a-mac-screen-saver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/making-a-mac-screen-saver/</guid>
      <description>Having just completed the my first screen saver for Mac - the Time In Words Screen Saver, I thought I would share some of the experiences. I am using OS X Lion (10.7) and Xcode 4.3.2
The first thing is to create a new project in Xcode using the Screen Saver template:

Xcode sets up a project for you with everything you need for a screen saver module. Start editing the ScreenSaverView.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words Screen Saver</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words-screen-saver-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words-screen-saver-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>The latest member of the Time In Words suite of apps is a screen saver module for Macs.
Version 1.2 updated January 2013: compatible with Lion (OS X 10.7), Mountain Lion (OS X 10.8), Mavericks (OS X 10.9) &amp;amp; Yosemite (OS X 10.10).
Download Time In Words Screen Saver
Like Time In Words for iOS and World Time In Words for Mac, it displays the time and date in plain words which are easy to read and comprehend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>