<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iphone on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/iphone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iphone on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasting</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2016/podcasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/podcasting/</guid>
      <description>I have recently started what I hope will be a weekly podcast with my friend and colleague, Jerry Daniels. Each podcast will be about 30 minutes in length.
We will discuss Macs, iPhones, iPads, macOS, iOS, programming and anything tech-related that we find interesting. I hope you will find it entertaining and informative, so please join us.
We are using ZCast which has an iPhone app that makes it super easy to get together and record our chats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/apple-watch-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/apple-watch-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I realise that every one has written one of these posts, but given that everyone looks for and notices different things, I think it is still valid.
My first impression was &amp;ldquo;Why does it come in such a large box?&amp;rdquo;. The courier delivered two boxes - my 38mm Apple Watch Sport and Tim&amp;rsquo;s 42mm Apple Watch Sport. They both came in long boxes, with the 42mm box significantly longer. And both boxes were heavy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4 Home Button</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/iphone-4-home-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/iphone-4-home-button/</guid>
      <description>My iPhone 4 is now 18 months old, and it&amp;rsquo;s Home button is starting to feel the strain. These buttons have been used much more than originally intended, with the new multitasking required double-presses, not to mention access to the camera etc. So basically , it is wearing out.
The phone is out of warranty and there is no way I am going to pay for an expensive repair when my current phone contract will expire later this year, and hopefully the iPhone 5 will be ready for me then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>