<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apps on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apps on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 14:48:53 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Marktime</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/marktime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 14:48:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/marktime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;img {width: 300px; } &lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Time is now available now from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mark-time/id1305580742?mt=8&#34;&gt;iTunes App Store&lt;/a&gt; for iPhone and
iPad as an assistant for celestial navigators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/work/</guid>
      <description>Work is a project organizer app for developers, designers, students or any professional who works with multiple projects involving files &amp;amp; folders, web pages, email addresses and lists of tasks.
Work requires macOS 10.12 or OS X 10.11 and will be available from the Mac App Store soon.
We all know what it is like to be in the middle of a project or rushing to complete an assignment&amp;hellip;
We have files scattered all over the place, email addresses of team members or clients, web pages with specifications or useful information, tasks scribbled on sticky notes or scraps of paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is My Speed?</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/what-is-my-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/what-is-my-speed/</guid>
      <description>img { display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto }  &amp;ldquo;What Is My Speed?&amp;rdquo; is available now from the iTunes App Store for iPhone and Apple Watch.
If you read my recent blog post on Road Trip Apps you will have realised that I was working on an app to fill a gap that I discovered in our road trip app arsenal. So here it is: &amp;ldquo;What Is My Speed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dice Pass</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/dicepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/dicepass/</guid>
      <description>Dice Pass is available from the Mac App Store.
Dice Pass is a utility to app to generate random passphrases based on the Diceware system. Diceware uses a table of pre-defined words, each assigned a 5 digit code number containing the digits 1 to 6. The official way to generate a phrase is to roll 5 dice for each word you want in your passphrase and then consult the words table to find the matching word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19th Hole</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/19th-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/19th-hole/</guid>
      <description>19th Hole is the golf scoring app for everyone, and it is available from the iTunes App Store.
Whether you are playing for the club championship, having a weekend round with friends or playing pitch&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;putt with the kids, 19th Hole makes it easy to keep score.
Designed for fast, accurate score keeping with a color scheme chosen for optimal outdoor viewing, 19th Hole uses a simple setup process and an intuitive, gesture-based score entry system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Time In Words</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/world-time-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/world-time-in-words/</guid>
      <description>World Time In Words version 3.0 is now available in the Mac App Store.
With version 3.0 of this app, I have changed the name to &amp;ldquo;World Time In Words&amp;rdquo;. This is to reflect what I feel to be the most useful feature of this app: the ability to convert between time zones.
It has two other new features:
 The time shown in the menu bar can now be set to use 24-hour time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berio&#39;s Sequenza VII</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/berio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/berio/</guid>
      <description>Luciano Berio wrote a series of Sequenzas for various instruments with Sequenza VII being the one for oboe.
Preparing this work creates some unique problems for the oboist as Berio did not adhere to any time signature that could be indicated by a metronome. Instead, each line consists of 13 bars (measures) with each bar&amp;rsquo;s length specified in exact seconds.
When my son (an oboist currently studying in Melbourne, Australia) started trying to learn this piece, it occurred to him that having an iOS app developer in the family could be of some assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icns Maker</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icns-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icns-maker/</guid>
      <description>Icns Maker is available from the Mac App Store.
Make an icns in 2 steps: 
 Drag an image into the window.
 Click “Create icns” or “Create assets”.
  This creates a .icns file or assets folder that can be imported directly into your Xcode project for use in your app.
Why is this necessary? In versions of Xcode before 4.4, Apple provided an app called “Icon Composer”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Builder</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-builder/</guid>
      <description>Icon Builder 3.2 is available from the Mac App Store.
Make and install a set of icons for an iOS, Mac or Apple Watch app in 3 steps: 1: Drag an image into the window.
2: Choose the device family you are building for: iOS Universal, iPhone, iPad, Mac or Apple Watch.
If you are building for iOS and your app still supports iOS 6, then you need to change the setting in the iOS popup menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Knight&#39;s Move</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/knightsmove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/knightsmove/</guid>
      <description>A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move is a puzzle game where you have to move your knight across a board to a target square using the same movements as a knight in chess. Pawns may block your way, while enemy bishops, castles, knights and the queen may try to stop you.
UPDATE: Version 1.3 for Mac now available.
 Available from the Mac App Store for OS X 10.7 or later  Get from the starting position to the target in the shortest possible number of moves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man Reader</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/manreader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/manreader/</guid>
      <description>Man Reader is a utility app for reading macOS&amp;rsquo;s man pages. Man Reader allows quick, convenient and easy access to the man pages on your system, useful for programmers, system administrators and tweakers.

 Buy Man Reader from the Mac App Store  Man pages are available for the Unix commands used mostly in Terminal or when shell scripting. These man pages are normally displayed in Terminal using the &amp;ldquo;man&amp;rdquo; command e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words Screen Saver</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words-screen-saver-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words-screen-saver-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>The latest member of the Time In Words suite of apps is a screen saver module for Macs.
Version 1.2 updated January 2013: compatible with Lion (OS X 10.7), Mountain Lion (OS X 10.8), Mavericks (OS X 10.9) &amp;amp; Yosemite (OS X 10.10).
Download Time In Words Screen Saver
Like Time In Words for iOS and World Time In Words for Mac, it displays the time and date in plain words which are easy to read and comprehend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Time In Words for Mac</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>World Time In Words for Mac version 3.0 is now available through the Mac App Store. This update changes the name from &amp;ldquo;Time In Words&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;World Time In Words&amp;rdquo; as an acknowledgment that the major feature of this app is converting time between different time zones. This update adds the ability to show digital time if you need greater accuracy - just hold down Option as you open the menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words for iOS</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words/</guid>
      <description>Time In Words is a clock and calendar app that takes you out of the digital era and back to when saying &amp;ldquo;quarter to seven&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;five past two&amp;rdquo; was accurate enough. When people look at an analog watch, they tend to interpret the time to the closest five minutes which allows for inaccuracies in the watch as well as providing only a useful level of detail. This app goes back to that, showing date and/or time in multiple ways, but all in words.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>