<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 17:42:57 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2017/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 17:42:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2017/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I came to update my blog: I had a new post in draft form and I wanted
to update the Swift code to version 4. However installing High Sierra had
removed &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com&#34; title=&#34;Jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; which is the site generator that I had been using. I
re-installed Jekyll but found that it had been updated from version 2 to version
3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting from my new iPad</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2017/posting-from-my-new-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2017/posting-from-my-new-ipad/</guid>
      <description>Last week I got a 10.5” iPad Pro. I have had an iPad ever since the original release, but I have to confess to mainly using it for content consumption rather than creation. Since I am usually close to a Mac anyway, there didn’t seem a lot of point. But now that iOS 11 is really addressing the issue of making the iPad a &amp;ldquo;pro&amp;rdquo; device, I decided to give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing automation</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/testing-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/testing-automation/</guid>
      <description>Today I am experimenting with automating post generation.
Firstly, there is the structure of the post Markdown document, which really boils down to the file name and the header.
I have set up a macro in Typinator so that I just type the title of the post in a text document. I copy that title to the clipboard and type the shortcut. The header is then created with the title and the formatted permalink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow for writing a post</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2015/workflow-for-writing-a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/workflow-for-writing-a-post/</guid>
      <description>So here is where I need to get used to Jekyll and how things are done. I will end up automating this when I am sure of the process, but for now, I am just going to work my way through it.
 Start up the local Jekyll server:
 I opened Terminal and used cd to get to the folder containing my site. Next I started the Jekyll server locally using jekyll serve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>