<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>markdown on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in markdown on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<title>Workflow for writing a post</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2015/workflow-for-writing-a-post/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/workflow-for-writing-a-post/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So here is where I need to get used to Jekyll and how things are done. I will
end up automating this when I am sure of the process, but for now, I am just
going to work my way through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start up the local Jekyll server:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I opened Terminal and used &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; to get to the folder containing my site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next I started the Jekyll server locally using &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This gave me the address of the local server - in my case
&lt;code&gt;http://127.0.0.1:4000/&lt;/code&gt; - so I went there in my browser to see the default
page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My goal is to write a new blog post (this one in fact).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For advice on creating a new post, I went to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/posts/&#34;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jekyll needs the file name to be a specific format which includes the date
and title.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; folder of the site folder, I see the previous post
file is titled &lt;code&gt;2015-03-08-new-site-for-trozware.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As it is now 10th March 2015, I am saving this file as:
&lt;code&gt;2015-03-10-workflow-for-writing-a-post.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving at this point shows a Jekyll error in the Terminal, but the next
stage will fix that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front matter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jekyll specifies that each file must have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&#34;&gt;front matter block&lt;/a&gt; in a
certain format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The header has certain essential parameters and then more optional ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My site was imported from WordPress, so the older posts contain several
header parameters that may not be necessary any more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the screen shot below to see what I have in this post file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After saving, I see this entry in my Terminal:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Regenerating: 1 file(s) changed at 2015-03-10 13:50:40 ...done in 0.421789
seconds.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now I can see the title and the start of the post on my first page and when
clicking on it, I can see all the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding an image:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is not really necessary for this post, but I wanted to document it as
part of the workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to show the front matter and start of this post, so I took a
screen shot of the top of my editor window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I renamed the image file and moved it into the &lt;code&gt;images&lt;/code&gt; folder of my
site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now to embed the image using this Markdown: &lt;code&gt;![Post header][2]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you can see, I prefer to group all links (images &amp;amp; URLs) at the end of
the document and keep the body of the text as clean as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troz.net/images/post_header.png&#34; alt=&#34;Post header&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proofing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now that I have the text of my post, I need to proof-read it from the local
Jekyll server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; command running in Terminal keeps the pages up-to-date
as you edit, but you will need to refresh your page in the browser manually
to check your changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I have found that if you make a major change to the site e.g. a CSS
file or a config file, then it is best to stop the Jekyll server and start
it again to make it re-build all the files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be completely sure, stop the server and run &lt;code&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; in Terminal
although this may only do what &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; does on startup anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now it is time to publish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I am using GitHub Pages to host, the site files are all part of a single
Git repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And as I understand it, the data &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be in the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opening up the GitHub client, I see that my repository has a bunch of
changes: - the file I am working on - the image I inserted - feed.xml -
index.html files for each page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is as expected, since all pages are pre-generated when using Jekyll,
so pages of posts must be re-rendered when a new post is added to the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that several of the files appear twice: once from where they are
edited and once from the _site folder which serves them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just two simple steps now, using the GitHub client: 1. Commit 2. Sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it. My new post is online and ready for reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was my first post after the one I wrote when setting up, so the first
real post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While there appear to be a lot of steps, none of them are difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But I do have 4 apps running to do it: 1. TextWrangler for editing 1.
Terminal to run the local Jekyll server 1. Safari to check the finished
post 1. GitHub to commit and upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automating this is an obvious next step, so stay tuned&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Markdown</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2013/markdown/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2013/markdown/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;For some time now, I have been aware of the increasing trend towards using
Markdown for text editing and for creating HTML. Markdown has been on my list of
&amp;ldquo;things I should learn some day&amp;rdquo; so I was interested last week to read about a
new iBooks book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://macsparky.com/markdown&#34;&gt;The MacSparky Markdown Field Guide&lt;/a&gt;. This was
sufficient inspiration so I got the book and read through it this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.squarespace.com/static/5008676d84aeae82b8acdd8c/t/5147c7a6e4b0d224b4419401/1363658669971/Markdown%20Cover%20Art%20-%20JPG.jpg?format=500w&#34; alt=&#34;The MacSparky Markdown Field Guide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, to say that I &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; through the book is a mis-representation. The
book was written using iBooks Author specially for the iPad and contains screen
casts and interviews as well as text. But by the end of it, I now feel I have a
basic understanding on Markdown and the ways in which I can use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the really big thing about using Markdown is that is creates plain text
files that are human-readable even without being converted to HTML. This makes
them future-proof since they are not tied to a proprietary file format that may
cease to exist at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-markdown&#34;&gt;Using Markdown:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this web site is a self-hosted WordPress site, my next step was to look
for a WordPress plugin that would allow me to use Markdown to create my posts. I
could have used a Markdown editor that had HTML export, but I wanted to try
something that would eliminate the extra step. The first one I decide to try was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/markdown-on-save-improved/&#34;&gt;Markdown on Save Improved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for choosing this one was that it stores the posts as
both Markdown and as HTML. This saves time when going back to edit a post,
avoids the constant changes that creep in when converting between formats all
the time, and makes it so that the post will still display correctly even if
Markdown is no longer supported. The only problem I have found so far is that it
doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically create links &amp;amp; image links using the Markdown format, but
uses standard &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; links instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next stop, since I always use a Mac, was to get Brett Terpstra&amp;rsquo;s collection
of &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com/projects/markdown-service-tools/&#34;&gt;Services for Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. These add a lot on convenient shortcuts: one of
my favourites is the ability to convert inline links to references links for
increased readability while editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-impressions&#34;&gt;First Impressions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So having written this first post in Markdown, how do I feel about it? I haven&amp;rsquo;t
really tried anything too weird this time, but there are a few things that were
very easy to do. Particularly in the paragraph where I was talking about links &amp;amp;
images and wanted to include the tags as text without having it interpreted as
HTML. All I had to do was surround the text with back-ticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are vastly easier to manage and edit in Markdown. I miss the ability to
specify that links should open in a new tab - I prefer to have that setting for
links that take you outside my web site, but the modern theories on usability
seem to be heading towards deprecation of this feature, so I may just stop using
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the standard WordPress editor, I always felt that I was fighting it. I had
to swap between the visual &amp;amp; HTML editor tabs and when I swapped tabs, things
would sometimes change without me doing anything. So far, I feel more in control
using Markdown and although I have lost the WYSIWYG visual editor, I no longer
have to wade through the HTML editor to get the effect I want or to remove the
results of a few careless clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things on my wish list would be solved by a better editor and some
by more powerful syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding links &amp;amp; images using Markdown style instead of HTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being able to create lists

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown makes this very easy but this WP plugin does not support lists as
far as I can tell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So these lists are in HTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alignment of text &amp;amp; images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a stand-alone Markdown editor would solve the editor questions, but I
wanted to try writing this post completely in WordPress.&lt;br /&gt;
And with the alignment, there is nothing to stop me adding CSS to the Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, I will test out a different WordPress Markdown editor and see how
that goes. I will also test using a standalone editor and exporting its HTML to
create a post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>