<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>operating systems on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/operating-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in operating systems on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/operating-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating apps for iPhone 5</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/updating-apps-for-iphone-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/updating-apps-for-iphone-5/</guid>
      <description>I have started work updating my iOS apps to fill the larger screen of an iPhone
 My iPhone 5 is on order - I missed out on the first shipment, but hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be too long. Meanwhile, I will just test in the iPhone Simulator and hope this is OK.  But it was a puzzle to me how to get an app to fill the longer screen. I have the latest Xcode and the latest Simulator which allows you to specify what screen size iPhone to simulate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy access to the Library folder</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/easy-access-to-the-library-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/easy-access-to-the-library-folder/</guid>
      <description>In Mac OS X 10.7 (Lion), Apple decided to make it more difficult to access your Library folder, presumably to stop people doing stuff that made apps crash. But as a developer, I need access to my Library folder a lot. I need to check that preferences are being saved correctly. If I have an app that uses the Application Support folder, then I need to be able to check it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for older operating systems</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/post/2012/support-for-older-operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2012/support-for-older-operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>Working out what operating systems to support in your software is always a difficult decision. I only program for Mac &amp;amp; iOS systems for starters. This is because they are the systems I use and understand. I am not interested in expending the time &amp;amp; money needed to program and test my software for other systems.
Within the Mac &amp;amp; iOS ecosystems, there is still the decision of which versions to support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>