<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>passwords on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/passwords/</link>
    <description>Recent content in passwords on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/passwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<title>Dice Pass Updated</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-updated/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-updated/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/dicepass/&#34;&gt;Dice Pass 1.1&lt;/a&gt; is now available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id997688302&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-dice-pass-do&#34;&gt;What does Dice Pass do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is a utility to app to generate random passphrases based on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/diceware.html&#34;&gt;Diceware&lt;/a&gt; system. Diceware uses a table of pre-defined words, each assigned
a 5 digit code number containing the digits 1 to 6. The official way to generate
a phrase is to roll 5 dice for each word you want in your passphrase and then
consult the words table to find the matching word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting phrase uses real words or common abbreviations so it is easier to
remember than a random collection of characters. At the same time, the random
selection of words makes the generated passphrase much more secure as it avoids
the human tendency to pick words with personal meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass allows you to select the number of words in your passphrase,
re-generate the entire passphrase any time, re-roll a single word in your
passphrase or set the dice rolls manually for maximum security and randomness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-new-in-version-1-1&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in Version 1.1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now select from three word lists in the Word Lists menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;original Diceware list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beale list (fewer Americanisms and obscure words)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diceware 8k list (a list of words that is a whole power of two in length)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also import your own word list if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass 1.1 is compatible with macOS Sierra.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>