<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TrozWare</title>
    <description>macOS, iOS and watchOS Developer</description>
    <link>http://troz.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://troz.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Posting from my new iPad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I got a 10.5” iPad Pro. I have had an iPad ever since the original release, but I have to confess to mainly using it for content consumption rather than creation. Since I am usually close to a Mac anyway, there didn’t seem a lot of point. But now that iOS 11 is really addressing the issue of making the iPad a “pro” device, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, sitting in an armchair with my iPad on my lap, writing this post and working out the details as I go. Any typos are due to the cat trying to compete with the iPad for space on my lap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ipad&quot;&gt;iPad:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned, I have a new iPad Pro. I also have an Apple Pencil which I use for taking notes. I do not have a keyboard, so I am using the on-screen keyboard right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually install beta versions of operating systems, but iOS 11 is a huge  part of making the iPad more professional, so I have installed it. As you would expect, there are a few issues (apps quitting, layout issues especially when rotating) but so far I am loving it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My site is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; with all the posts and pages written in Markdown. One key feature is that every post or page requires a chunk of “front matter” that must be formatted correctly for the Jekyll parser to interpret it and create the static content. After a bit of research, it looked like &lt;a href=&quot;http://omz-software.com/editorial/&quot;&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt; was going to be the best option for an editor app. I moved my site files to Dropbox, linked my Dropbox account to Editorial and I was ready to start writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to create the front matter manually for each post. On my Mac I have a text expander snippet that handles that but copying from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mattgemmell.com/using-the-ipad-for-blogging-with-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Matt Gemell’s post&lt;/a&gt; on the topic, I created an Editorial workflow to create a new post. As a side-note, Matt has a series of posts on using an iPad which I have found very useful and inspirational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/Workflow.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Editorial workflow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text entry and editing is a task that I have always felt was too difficult in iOS, particularly when it came to selecting text and moving the cursor. However there are now several improvements. As with iOS 10, a two-fingered press on the keyboard transforms it into a trackpad for moving the cursor. If you already have text selected, this moves the selection handles. The new iOS 11 keyboard has a really nice feature for entering non-alphabetic characters. The keys now show a small grey character above the main character. Drag down on the key to move the small character into the main key and type it. For example, drag down on the h key to type (.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/keyboard-drag.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard drag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editorial has its own editing helpers. There is an additional toolbar above the keyboard with a tab key as well as frequently used Markdown modifiers. And swiping across this toolbar moves the cursor. This is a much slower move than when using the keyboard as a trackpad so might be better for more precise movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;adding-links&quot;&gt;Adding Links:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have referenced a few sites now, so I guess it is time to work out how to link to them. I always use Markdown’s  referenced link method, with the links collected at the foot of the document, so that is what I plan to do here. To set text as a link, I selected it and used the Editorial toolbar to type an opening square bracket which surrounded the selection in square brackets. Then I moved the cursor to after the closing bracket and typed another opening square bracket. This auto-closed and I was able to type a number which will be the reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to find the relevant URLs - drag &amp;amp; drop with multi-tasking to the rescue! Swipe up from the bottom of the screen to see the new Dock. This also makes the keyboard disappear. Hold down on the Safari icon until you grab it, then drag it up into the Editorial window. Now it is open as an overlay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/safari-overlay.png&quot; alt=&quot;Safari as overlay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I have several options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swiping from the left or right of the overlay window lets me position it to the right or left of the screen, still as an overlay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dragging from the bar at the top of the overlap allows me to convert to split screen mode, and I can then drag the divider to adjust the ratios.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swiping all the way to the right disappears the overlay, but swiping back from the right edge returns it. Since I want to copy and paste some links, this looks like the best option right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This swiping conflicts slightly with Editorial’s swiping from the side to see a preview. Swipe from off the edge for the overlap and from well inside the edge for preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here my plans come crashing down. I can drag from Safari’s address bar into the Editorial document, but the drop doesn’t take. I guess I need an update to Editorial for this to work. But I can still use the old style copy and paste to get the links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;images&quot;&gt;Images:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have my links, but I want to insert a few images. I used iOS 11’s new screen shot abilities. Press the usual home button &amp;amp; power button combination to take a screen shot and it appears as a small picture in the bottom left of the screen. Tap it to start editing: markup, crop etc. Then I used the sharing button to save the picture to Dropbox, putting it inside the images folder in my web site folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/screenshot.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Editing a screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to insert an image link but I have just worked out that I saved this Markdown file in the root folder instead of the _posts folder. I can’t see a way to move it from inside Editorial, so I will swap to the Dropbox app to move the file - be right back…  (I see now how I could have done this in Editorial.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, this file is in the right place and the images are in the right folder, so how to add an image link? Checking back at previous posts, I see that the format I use for inserting an image is: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;![Alt text][#]&lt;/code&gt; and the reference at the foot of the page is like&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[#]: {{ site.url }}/images/image_name.jpg&lt;/code&gt; but I don’t want to have to remember that every time, so I think it is time for some snippets. Tapping the lightning icon on the Editorial keyboard lets me edit and create snippets, so I have made one for the image link and one for the image reference. Time to scroll back up the page and try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened the Dropbox app in an overlay so that I could find the file names for the images I just saved, then I created the links. The images don’t appear in the preview but that is expected because Jekyll has not parsed the addresses. Looking at the information about the images in Dropbox, I see that they are far too big. I need a way to resize them. The screen shot editor doesn’t have a way to resize apart from cropping, at least not in this beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is/&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt; is another Pro level app that I have never really used, but it seems that it might do the job. I tried a few workflows to edit the size of an image from a Dropbox file and save it back, but they although they appeared to complete, the image file remained the same size. So then I went to the Workflow Gallery and found a workflow called Quick Resize Screenshot. When editing a screen shot, I can use the sharing button to run the workflow and then I can save the smaller images to Dropbox for use in the page. For the large images that I have already saved, I will resize them on my Mac before publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;publishing&quot;&gt;Publishing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the final step - publishing the changes to GitHub Pages. Jekyll is a system that creates static web pages from the Markdown and other files. on my Mac, I run the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; command in Terminal and the pages are created or re-generated as required. Then I use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to commit my changes and push them to GitHub which serves them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appear to be Editorial workflows written in Python that use the GitHub APIs to upload files, but this wouldn’t work well for me. Because of the structure of my site, many different pages need to be re-generated when I publish a new post, so I will keep the publishing phase on my Mac. However there is no need to make it any more difficult than necessary, so I have written a shell script to do the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script takes an optional commit message parameter, builds the site, commits changes and pushes then to GitHub. I have only tested this when no files had changed, so this post will be the first real test. Shell scripting is outside my comfort zone, so we will have to see how that works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have a workflow on my iPad that uses Editorial, Dropbox and Workflow. This allows me to do 100% of the writing task. Then I have a single shell script on my Mac that does the publishing part. I can edit and create posts anywhere. I can easily use split screen or screen overlays to add links. iOS 11 makes creating and annotating screen shots very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping for an update to Editorial that will allow it to accept drag &amp;amp; drop. The ability to resize screen shots before saving them would also be really useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes my posts are more code-based and need access to Xcode and in those cases, I will stick to my Mac, especially considering Xcode’s new ability to connect directly to GitHub which will make it great for publishing Swift playgrounds. But for more narrative-style posts like this one, I will use my iPad and see how I can improve my workflow and expand my tool set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels good to be using the iPad as a content creation device at last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extra-notes-from-a-mac&quot;&gt;Extra Notes from a Mac:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this was my first time writing a blog post using an iPad and this workflow, I decided that I should test the results before publishing, so I switched back to the Mac and in Terminal, ran &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; so that I could see the results. There were a few issues mainly to do with the formatting of the front matter. The three dashes at the top &amp;amp; bottom of the front matter had become munged into an emdash plus a dash, so that didn’t work. Jekyll is also fussy about the spaces in the tag &amp;amp; summary lines and it doesn’t handle non-alphanumerics in the summary text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used the Mac to shrink some of the images that I had saved before working out how to reduce the size of screen shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I need to check the structure of the front matter workflow before next time, but this post is ready to go with only minor editing on the Mac side. Now to test my shell script…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2017/06/posting-from-my-new-ipad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2017/06/posting-from-my-new-ipad</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JSON Feed for TrozWare</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonfeed.org/2017/05/17/announcing_json_feed&quot;&gt;jsonfeed.org&lt;/a&gt; has announced a new format for web site feeds, designed as an alternative to RSS. TrozWare has had an XML RSS feed for years, but I don’t think anyone ever uses it (I certainly don’t), so today I have replaced it with a JSON feed, which you can access through the &lt;a class=&quot;fa fa-rss&quot; href=&quot;/feed.json&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; button at the top of every page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure many JSON Feed viewers will appear soon, but the only one I know about so far is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://json-feed-viewer.herokuapp.com&quot;&gt;http://json-feed-viewer.herokuapp.com&lt;/a&gt;. As soon as this update to my site goes live, I will apply to have TrozWare added to the list of sites on this page. Meanwhile, you can paste in the URL: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://troz.net/feed.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is constructed using Jekyll, so I am very grateful to Niclas Darville for his very easy to follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://ndarville.com/blog/2017/05/19/json-feed-for-jekyll/&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;. However it is still well worth reading through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonfeed.org/version/1&quot;&gt;official specs&lt;/a&gt; to see what else you want to add, or if you want to remove anything. I had to tweak a few settings to make it work for my configuration, and I added some more objects, but Niclas got me off to a flying start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things to watch out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure your feed is producing valid JSON (I had an extra comma that was breaking it…).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As third-party apps &amp;amp; sites may be displaying your content, you need to make sure that you are not using relative URLs for images and internal links. I was using relative image URLs like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/images/WorkHelp1.png&lt;/code&gt; but that showed a broken link in the feed viewer, so I have changed all such links to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;site.url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;}/images/WorkHelp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;.png&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Hopefully that will work correctly on my local test server as well as when published.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jsonfeed.org/graphics/icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;JSON Feed icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON Feed offers a nice icon which I would have liked to use, but I could not work out a way to make it play nicely with the existing icons on my pages which all use &lt;a href=&quot;http://fontawesome.io&quot;&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; icons. So I ended up just using the existing Feed icon. Hopefully Font Awesome will soon add a JSON Feed icon to their already impressive list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone still wants to use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, it is no longer linked to the buttons at the top of the pages, but you can access it manually.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2017/05/json-feed-for-trozware/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2017/05/json-feed-for-trozware/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blackmail Marketing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use my iPad to play games as a form of  relaxation. Nearly all the games I play are puzzle apps with levels that can be played in a few minutes. Nearly all of them are free to install. So how do they make money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I would be the last person you should consult about marketing but it has always seemed to me that the best way to market your product is to convince people that it offers something they want so that they are prepared to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the currently favored approach for mobile apps - at least certainly not for games. No, the theory at the moment is to cause so much frustration and annoyance that people give you money to make it stop. Blackmail marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A frequently used method is showing ads, sometimes just banner ads but more often full screen video ads that run for up to 30 seconds. If you interrupt the ad, you don’t get the reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every goal reached triggers an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quitting and resuming the app triggers an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wanting to play another level triggers an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory is that you get so annoyed with this that you pay money to disable the ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other common tactic is the delay. A tower defence game needs you to build a tower? OK, that will take 12 hours real time and you can’t proceed until it’s finished. Or you can spend 12 gems which are sold as an in-app purchase. Maybe you can only play 3 levels and then you need to recharge: again, pay up or wait. You keep dying on that level? You’re out of lives. Pay up or wait until tomorrow. These delays are completely artificial. They have nothing to do with game play but are solely designed to infuriate you enough to get you to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when, and perhaps more importantly why, did mobile app marketing become so negative? What happened to making your customers happy? Do unhappy customers spend more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financially, it appears that irritating your users is a successful strategy. Nearly all the top grossing games in the App Store are “free to play” in that the initial download costs nothing. But these big studios are raking in enormous sums of money, so many people are persuaded to spend significant money by these infuriating schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large part of this must be due to the various App Stores driving prices to the bottom. Gone are the days when the price of a mobile app was other than risible. So app developers have four choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do it as a hobby or learning exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distribute apps as a form of self–promotion for other work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work for someone who pays you a real wage to develop apps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Join the blackmailers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does this relate to indy developers like me? I care about my users and want them to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried several different approaches to app distribution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Totally free gets by far the most downloads but is economically ridiculous unless the app adds value to your business in some other way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A tip jar gets you nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In-app purchases (in my limited experience) make less than selling the app up-front for a small price.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Banner ads with no method of forcing people to watch them generate almost no revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that leaves me with where I am today - selling apps for a few dollars and nothing more. Happily, I have found that Mac users are more prepared to pay a few dollars for an app, so I have shut down many of my iOS apps and am concentrating on the Mac app market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I letting my principles stand in the way of mobile app profits? Should I just join the gang and start blackmailing my customers? If so, what form should this take?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I am considering banner ads on the screen with an in-app purchase to disable them entirely. I read a suggestion for a less invasive method of doing this by creating your own ads for your other apps. This might be what I end up doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would welcome any suggestions, advice or comments. Please join the discussion below or contact me using one of the links at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2017/03/blackmail-marketing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2017/03/blackmail-marketing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NCSS 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl&quot;&gt;IBM Swift Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sandbox-code-samples&quot;&gt;Sandbox Code Samples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/58670662da20a814737c3562&quot;&gt;Strings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5868463fb5619f13e0a940af&quot;&gt;Optionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5868954cb5619f13e0a940bd&quot;&gt;Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5866f31fda20a814737c353b&quot;&gt;Closures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5866f48bda20a814737c353c&quot;&gt;Objects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5866ed80da20a814737c3538&quot;&gt;Protocols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://swiftlang.ng.bluemix.net/#/repl/5866fc4dda20a814737c3557&quot;&gt;Generics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contact-details&quot;&gt;Contact Details:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sarah@troz.net?subject=NCSS%202017&quot;&gt;sarah@troz.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trozware&quot;&gt;@trozware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Slides: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/09r19my3d6jk5jt/NCSS%202017%20Swift%20MC.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;NCSS 2017 Swift MC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;useful-links&quot;&gt;Useful Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/au/book/swift-programming-language/id881256329?mt=11&quot;&gt;The Swift Programming Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://swift.org&quot;&gt;Swift.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/132258/top-5-ios-swift-newsletters&quot;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com&quot;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/ncss2017/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/ncss2017/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for beta testers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am looking for beta testers for my latest Mac app: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/work/&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; is a project organizer app for developers, designers, students or any professional who works with multiple projects involving files &amp;amp; folders, web pages, email addresses and lists of tasks. Click the link above for more information and help for getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; requires macOS 10.12 or OS X 10.11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to test this app, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:work@troz.net?subject=Work%20beta%20test&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;, giving details of your Mac and operating system. The easiest way to do this is to select &lt;strong&gt;About This Mac&lt;/strong&gt; in the Apple menu and send me a screen shot of the window that appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All beta testers will receive a free license to Work when it is released.
If you report a legitimate bug or provide valuable feed-back, you will also receive a free license to your choice of one of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/applications/&quot;&gt;other apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/11/looking-for-beta-testers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/11/looking-for-beta-testers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; is a project organizer app for developers, designers, students or any professional who works with multiple projects involving files &amp;amp; folders, web pages, email addresses and lists of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; requires macOS 10.12 or OS X 10.11 and will be available from the Mac App Store soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know what it is like to be in the middle of a project or rushing to complete an assignment…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have files scattered all over the place, email addresses of team members or clients, web pages with specifications or useful information, tasks scribbled on sticky notes or scraps of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be better if there was one place where you could have quick and easy access to all these items, but without having to change the way you work? With the &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; app, you can regain control - the app helps you get to what you want so you save time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the project document you will see when you select &lt;strong&gt;Work Help&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Help&lt;/strong&gt; menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/WorkHelp1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gathers together some useful links to information about &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; and my other apps or to allow you to contact me. In &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; documents for my apps, I assemble the project files I need to open, images, web page addresses etc. My most frequently used links are starred so I can focus on them whenever I want a shorter list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drag files or folders into the window to link them to your &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; document. Copy a web address or email address and use &lt;strong&gt;Add Web/Email&lt;/strong&gt; to quickly create a new link entry with the copied address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switching to &lt;strong&gt;Tasks&lt;/strong&gt; mode allows you to focus on your tasks list. Tasks can be grouped, re-ordered and marked as complete. Use the &lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt; menu to hide completed tasks if you want a more compact list. Use the &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; menu or the toolbar buttons to edit groups - this allows you to create your own custom groupings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/WorkHelp2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Work - Tasks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t move or rename any of your files - it merely links all these things together for fast, convenient and searchable access. It even tracks files or folders if you move them later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; document for every project, drag in the relevant files or folders, add web page addresses and email addresses, make your own task lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create groups to gather items together, adjust the display to view only the entries you want, use quick look to get a fast glimpse of files or web pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work also supports the Touch Bar on the new MacBook Pros:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/Work_TB.png&quot; alt=&quot;Work - TouchBar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Work Help&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;strong&gt;Help&lt;/strong&gt; menu to see the special &lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt; document pictured above. Use the links to keep in touch and step through the sequence of tasks to learn the basics of using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Man Reader Update...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick update to &lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/manreader/&quot;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; to version 1.8 is now available through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for this version was that Man Reader was not previously detecting man pages installed by third-party IDEs in the Applications folder. There was also an issue with Man Reader failing to display the text of the previously selected man page on app launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More complete search for man pages, including in third-party IDEs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix for glitch when displaying previously selected page on launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/11/another-man-reader-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/11/another-man-reader-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man Reader Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/manreader/&quot;&gt;Man Reader&lt;/a&gt; has just been updated to version 1.7 and is available through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for this update was to make the app work well with macOS Sierra, as I found that version 1.6 was sometimes crashing on launch. While doing this, the update was rejected by the App Store reviewers because it crashed on OS X 10.10. Since I no longer have a Mac running 10.10, I decided to set the minimum supported system version to OS X 10.11. If you need support for older versions, you should still be able to download version 1.6 which will work back to 10.7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity to fix some graphical issues, dealing with different color schemes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The man page list now shows alternating colors even when not using the default scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When scrolling the man pages past the top or the bottom with a non-white background, you should no longer see white blocks top &amp;amp; bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/10/man-reader-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/10/man-reader-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcasting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently started what I hope will be a weekly podcast with my friend and colleague, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jerrydaniels&quot;&gt;Jerry Daniels&lt;/a&gt;. Each podcast will be about 30 minutes in length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will discuss Macs, iPhones, iPads, macOS, iOS, programming and anything tech-related that we find interesting. I hope you will find it entertaining and informative, so please join us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://zcast.co/zcasts&quot;&gt;ZCast&lt;/a&gt; which has an iPhone app that makes it super easy to get together and record our chats. It doesn’t allow any post-processing, but really lowers the barrier to entry into the world of podcasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/zcast-podcast-from-your-phone!/id1041586670&quot;&gt;ZCast app for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, go to the ZCasters tab and search for “Trozware” or “Jerry Daniels” to find all our podcasts. Or use these links to listen in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zcast.co/j/ZyB8yK4z86&quot;&gt;The new macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zcast.co/j/ewQe6x6E4d&quot;&gt;Hands-on with iPhone 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zcast.co/j/A9zvLAAEa3&quot;&gt;Hands on iOS 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the first one was recorded using my name instead of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trozware&quot;&gt;@trozware&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account, I will embed it here as it will not show up if you search for “Trozware”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://zcast.co/embedded/ZyB8yK4z86&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;width: 350; height: 500; border: none;&quot; scrolling=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/10/podcasting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/10/podcasting/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How much work does Icon Builder save you?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://troz.net/icon-builder/&quot;&gt;Icon Builder&lt;/a&gt; is a Mac app that takes a single image file and creates all the different image sizes that you need to make a set of icons for your app: Mac, iPhone, iPad, iOS Universal or Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4, released 16 September 2016 is available through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/icon-builder/id552293482&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-new-in-version-4&quot;&gt;What’s New in Version 4:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added support for iMessage apps and Sticker Pack apps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added support for creating Mac .icns files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better removal of alpha channel for Apple Watch icons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clearer usage instructions in ReadMe files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iTunes Artwork folders will no longer be over-written with the latest image files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supports macOS Sierra and Xcode 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://troz.net/images/IconBuilder.png&quot; alt=&quot;Icon Builder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working on version 4 and accommodating all these new icon sets (and wishing I had the time to re-write the app in Swift…), I counted up all the icon files that Icon Builder makes for each app type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;App Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Number of Icons&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iPhone supporting pre iOS 7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iPad supporting pre iOS 7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iOS Universal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iOS Universal supporting pre iOS 7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Apple Watch (also requires iOS app icons)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Sticker Pack app&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iMessages app&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;iMessages app Messages extension&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as you can see, Icon Builder is doing a lot of work for you. It also names all the icon files using the expected format, stores them in an concept folder, creates the JSON file that identifies them all to Xcode and optionally installs them in your Xcode project automatically. That’s a lot of value for dragging in an icon and clicking a button!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next time your designer sends you the twentieth tweaked icon for the day, don’t get mad. Just drop it into Icon Builder and sit back while it does all the work. (No need to tell the designer that…)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/09/how-much-work-does-icon-builder-save-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/09/how-much-work-does-icon-builder-save-you/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
