<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TrozWare</title>
    <description>Mac &amp;amp; iOS Developer</description>
    <link>http://troz.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://troz.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>New Twitter account</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have started a new Twitter account so that I can provide rapid support to users of my apps.
Please contact me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trozware&quot;&gt;@trozware&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions, suggestions, bug reports or would just like to chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also be using this account to promote my new &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/02/learning-swift-an-introduction/&quot;&gt;Learning Swift&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/02/new-twitter-account/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/02/new-twitter-account/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning Swift - An Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;welcome-to-learning-swift&quot;&gt;Welcome to Learning Swift.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in what I hope will be an extensive series dealing with the Swift language. Here are some of the questions I hope to answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should I learn Swift? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why is Swift do great?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How should I start learning Swift?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I already know Objective-C - how do I convert?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I am planning a series of posts discussing the major differences of Swift from the view point of an Objective-C programmer and the aspects of Swift that I found difficult to grasp. Topics covered will include such things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;optionals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;closures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;functional programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;protocols&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;generics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am coming from a background of Objective-C, so many of my posts will be dealing with aspects of Swift that are not familiar to Objective-C programmers. I will not assume any Objective-C programming experience, but some features of Swift that are new to me, will be familiar to people accustomed to other languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s start by answering the first question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;should-i-learn-swift&quot;&gt;Should I learn Swift?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are writing or planning apps for any Apple platform - YES.&lt;br /&gt;
If not, wait until Swift is available for the platforms you need to support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-are-already-an-ios-or-mac-developer-yes&quot;&gt;If you are already an iOS or Mac developer: YES&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the new language and Apple is very committed to it. Objective-C is not going away any time soon, but Swift is where it is going to end up, so why not make the jump now while the language is still in development? You have to accept that fact that every release of Xcode is going to break your code, but the automatic re-factoring works very well. And by moving to Swift now, you get the chance to influence the direction of a new language. How often does that happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-are-starting-to-learn-ios-or-mac-development-yes&quot;&gt;If you are starting to learn iOS or Mac development: YES&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have no history with Objective-C, then do not waste your time learning it. There is still a lot of sample code out there in Objective-C, but increasing numbers of tutorial sites are using Swift and converting their existing tutorials to Swift. It will help if you know just enough Objective-C to read it, but you do not need to know enough to write it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-do-not-program-for-mac-or-ios-not-yet&quot;&gt;If you do NOT program for Mac or iOS: NOT YET&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swift went open source in late 2015. This is a big deal and Apple’s plans for Swift are quite clear. They want Swift to be such a main-stream language that it is used instead of Java for basic computer science courses in universities. This was never going to happen unless the language was open-source and cross-platform. It is now open-source and available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://swift.org/download/#latest-development-snapshots&quot;&gt;Linux as well as Mac/iOS&lt;/a&gt;. While Apple has not yet released any further ports, I think there are more on the way for Raspberry Pi, Arduino and other embedded systems as well as server-side Swift libraries like &lt;a href=&quot;http://perfect.org&quot;&gt;Perfect&lt;/a&gt;. I expect that a version for Windows will not be far behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/02/learning-swift-an-introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/02/learning-swift-an-introduction/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Possible issues with Icon Builder &amp; Watch icons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that there are two possible issues with Icon Builder 3.0.1 when using icons created for an Apple Watch app.
Once of them is something I can fix and the other appears to be a bug in Xcode 7.2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Version 3.2 of Icon Builder has been submitted to the Mac App Store for review. This removes the alpha channel from icons for a watch app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first problem is that iTines Connect now requires that the icons for an Apple Watch app include no alpha channel. This is becoming an increasing trend with it first having applied to the large icon file you upload directly to iTunes Connect, then to screen shots. I expect it to extend to iOS app icons soon, but hopefully Mac app icons can continue to include transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Apple Watch icons, you are supposed to create a set of square icons and watchOS or iTunesConnect applies the rounding mask. Presumably this is more complicated if the icon contains an alpha channel even if there are no transparent pixels. If your Watch app icons contain an alpha channel, you will see errors like this after uploading your app to iTunes Connect:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Invalid Icon - The watch application ‘AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit App.app’ contains an icon file ‘AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit App.app/AppIcon-Watch24x24@2x.png’ with an alpha channel. Icons should not have an alpha channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will probably get this error message for every icon size in the Watch app (8 in total).
Until I release a new version of Icon Builder that allows for this this, I suggest you use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cocoacontrols.com/controls/alpha-channel-remover&quot;&gt;Alpha Channel Remover app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Xcode project, go to WatchKit App Assets.xcassets, select the AppIcon set, right-click and choose “Show in Finder”. A folder will open containing eight .png files and one .json file. Drag &amp;amp; drop the .png files into the Alpha Channel Remover window and click the “Remove Alpha Channel” button. This will replace all those image files with new versions without alpha channels. To confirm this, select any of the images and press Command-I to get info. In the More Info section, you will see “Alpha channel: No”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now submit your app again, but that only solves one of the issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that you will get a warning about the 44x44@2x.png icon file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Invalid Icon Name - The watch application ‘AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit App.app’ contains an invalid icon file name ‘AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit App.app/AppIcon-Watch44x44@2x.png’. Make sure that icon file names follow the pattern&lt;br /&gt; “&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*&amp;lt;dimension&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;scale&amp;gt;x.png&lt;/code&gt;” and they match the required dimensions. Please visit https://developer.apple.com/watchkit/ for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the error message, the icon name (which is set by Xcode) does conform to the required pattern, and the image is the correct size. This appears to be a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openradar.me/23801324&quot;&gt;bug in Xcode 7.2&lt;/a&gt; but does not stop you from submitting your app as it is only a warning and not an error. Presumably this will be fixed in later version of Xcode. I am running Xcode 7.2.1 and still see this warning.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/02/possible-issues-with-iconbuilder/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/02/possible-issues-with-iconbuilder/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick Score - Tennis</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- Quick Score: Tennis is available from the [iTunes App Store][1] for iPhone and Apple Watch. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick Score: Tennis will be available soon from the iTunes App Store for iPhone and Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick Score: Tennis is an app designed to allow you to score tennis matches quickly and easily on your iPhone or your Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/QST_Watch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quick Score: Tennis on Apple Watch&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Quick Score: Tennis on Apple Watch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When playing in a tennis match, your Apple Watch is the best way to score. Set your watch to resume last activity when raised and at the end of every point, a single tap is all it takes to record whether you won or lost the point. The watch will tell you the score for the current game as well as the score for the previous games and sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/QST1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quick Score: Tennis on iPhone&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Quick Score: Tennis on iPhone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any significant information is displayed: game won or lost, set won or last, match complete, change of ends, tie-breakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If scoring for a match that does not include you, the phone makes a good scoring device although the watch still works just as well. As with the watch, after every point it just takes a single tap to record the result of the point. The scores are displayed and significant information is announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone app records all matches played so any match can be reviewed later with the result of every game and set displayed. On the phone, the names of the players can be entered, either manually or by choosing from your contacts.  The result can be shared via email or message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/QST2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quick Score: Tennis summary&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Quick Score: Tennis summary on iPhone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No ads, no in-app purchases, no features missing - you get the complete app for less than the price of a can of tennis balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--If you like this app, please leave a rating or a review at the App Store. If you have a problem or want to suggest a new feature, please [contact me directly][2] so I can respond.--&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/quick-score-tennis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/quick-score-tennis/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man Reader 1.5</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Man Reader has been updated to version 1.5 with a major improvement in the way it looks for available man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/manreader/&quot;&gt;Man Reader 1.5&lt;/a&gt; is now available through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/man-reader/id522583774?mt=12&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;change-log&quot;&gt;Change Log:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Much improved searching for available man pages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sand-boxed version now works just as well as the non-sand-boxed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main feature of this version is that it solves the previous problems with the App Store version and sand-boxing. This was restricting the number of man pages listed in Man Reader so I had to release a non-sand-boxed version of the app to allow for full functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I discovered that although this gave better results, it was still missing a lot of man pages. Version 1.5 now queries the man page files in a completely different way which is listing many more man pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you previously had downloaded the Man Reader (no SB) version of the app from this site, please revert to the App Store version which you would have needed to have bought in order to use the downloaded app. If you bought the app from Paddle, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#104;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#122;&amp;#046;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#063;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#098;&amp;#106;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#061;&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#082;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#065;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#083;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; and I will transfer you to the App Store version. Neither of these other versions will be supported or updated any more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2016/01/man-reader-1.5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2016/01/man-reader-1.5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using 19th Hole on the Apple Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;19th Hole for iPhone and Apple Watch version 3 is now available through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/the-19th-hole/id871686159?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&quot;&gt;iTunes App Store&lt;/a&gt;.
This version is a complete re-write to accommodate the changes in iOS 9 and watchOS2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major changes are to do with the way the iPhone and the Watch communicate. In watchOS1, all the brains of the app had to live in the iPhone, meaning that every single interaction on the Watch had to be referred back to the iPhone for processing and the result sent back to the Watch for display. This lead to communications delays and breakdowns which caused third-party apps to work sluggishly or not at all. In watchOS2, the brains of the watch part of the app can now operate inside the watch, greatly reducing the number of communications needed. As well as that, Apple has now provided us with multiple ways of getting data to and from the Watch which again improves performance and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 19th Hole, I made the decision to change the method of inputting scores. The previous version used a slider with plus and minus buttons to adjust scores. The problems with this were the small target area of the plus &amp;amp; minus buttons as well as the fact that a slider with more than about 3 divisions was not useful as a visual indicator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When watchOS2 allowed developers access to the digital crown, I decided to switch to using that instead. Now you tap the score box of the player you wish to adjust and use the digital crown to select a number. I think this will be easier to use while wearing a glove and hope that it is still easy to read out doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other suggestion is not to do with watchOS2 but is a general tip for using apps of this kind. By default, the Apple Watch will always show the watch face when you raise your wrist. Normally this is the most useful thing, but when scoring a round of golf, it would be easier if The 19th Hole app stayed at the front. To make this happen, you need to set to watch to show the last used app instead of the watch face. This can be set using the Apple Watch app on the phone or on the watch itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the phone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the Apple Watch app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select My Watch from the tabs at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tap “General” and then scroll down to tap “Wake Screen”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure “Resume Last Activity” is checked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the watch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press the digital crown to see the app icons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find and tap the Settings icon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down and tap “General”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tap “Wake Screen” and scroll down to make sure that “Previous Activity” is checked in the “Resume To” section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2015/12/using-19th-hole-on-the-apple-watch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2015/12/using-19th-hole-on-the-apple-watch/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dice Pass for Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a world of passwords and passphrases and there is a constant struggle between having a secure and a memorable password. As a result, many of us re-use passwords even though we know this is a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/936/&quot;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; had a wonderful comic that illustrated the theory of using a passphrase composed of words that are easy to remember but with a combination that made the passphrase very hard to guess. However even when deciding to use a passphrase like this, it is not easy for us humans to avoid using words that have meaning for us, particularly when it is something we really need to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/diceware.html&quot;&gt;Diceware&lt;/a&gt; was developed to solve this problem. You have a set of 5 dice and a list of words assigned to each possible dice roll for 11111 to 66666. You roll the five dice and get the matching word from the list. Repeat this for the number of words you want to use in your passphrase and you have a random phrase that is hopefully still memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this sounds like a lot of effort and not something you are likely to do when faced by a password entry field on a web page. So &lt;a href=&quot;/dicepass/&quot;&gt;Dice Pass&lt;/a&gt; was written to do the work for you quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DicePass_Mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dice Pass for Mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the number of words you want in your passphrase and see the phrase immediately. Keep clicking the “Generate New Phrase” button until you get a phrase you like. If you feel that the computer is not to be trusted when generating a random number for the dice rolls, use your real dice and click the dice to change them to the roll you got. If you get a passphrase that is good except for one or two words, use the Re-Roll button beside those words to get a new roll for just that word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id997688302?mt=12&amp;amp;uo=4&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt; now and coming soon for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2015/05/dice-pass-for-mac/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2015/05/dice-pass-for-mac/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dice Pass</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dice-pass/id997688302&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt; for Mac OS X and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id998397511&quot;&gt;iTunes App Store&lt;/a&gt; for iPhone or iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is a utility to app to generate random passphrases based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/diceware.html&quot;&gt;Diceware system&lt;/a&gt;. Diceware uses a table of pre-defined words, each assigned a 5 digit code number containing the digits 1 to 6. The official way to generate a phrase is to roll 5 dice for each word you want in your passphrase and then consult the words table to find the matching word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DicePass_iOS.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dice Pass for Mac&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Dice Pass for iOS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DicePass_Mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dice Pass for Mac&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; Dice Pass for Mac&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting phrase uses real words or common abbreviations, so it is easier to remember than a random collection of characters. At the same time, the random selection of words makes the generated passphrase much more secure as it avoids the human tendency to pick words with personal meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Diceware system was invented by Arnold Reinhold. This utility is not associated with or supported by Arnold Reinhold in any way, but uses his techniques with thanks. For more information about Diceware, have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://world.std.com/%7Ereinhold/dicewarefaq.html&quot;&gt;Diceware Passphrase FAQ page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word list used in this app is a variation compiled by &lt;a href=&quot;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/beale.wordlist.asc&quot;&gt;Alan Beale&lt;/a&gt; that removes some of the more obscure words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;F.A.Q.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many words should I use in my passphrase?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arnold Reinhold recommends 6 words. He used to suggest that 5 was sufficient for most needs, but as of 2014 has increased this to 6. See the Diceware Passphrase FAQ page for more details. (Link above.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often can I re-generate the passphrase?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As often as you like. Keep clicking until you get a phrase that you can remember. If you get a phrase where most of the words are good but you would like to change one or two, you can click ‘Re-Roll’ on individual words to change them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a way to check the strength of my passphrase?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many password strength checkers on the internet and three of these are listed below. But always be careful when pasting your passphrase into a web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online password strength checkers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rumkin.com/tools/password/passchk.php&quot;&gt;Rumkin.com Strength Test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://howsecureismypassword.net&quot;&gt;How Secure Is My Password?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.passwordmeter.com&quot;&gt;The Password Meter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of the words in the phrase are not complete words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory is that shorter words or abbreviations are easier to remember than long ones, without compromising security. But if you get a word you don’t like or think that you will not be able to remember, just re-roll that word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I want to roll the dice myself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass allows you to tap on the 5 dice to set the numbers needed for each word manually. Each time you tap the number will go up be one, wrapping from 6 back to 1. The app will then look up the word table for you and show the new word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the phrase gets too long I can’t see all the words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Copy” button will copy the complete passphrase even if it is not all visible. You can also scroll by clicking and dragging along the passphrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does my passphrase get saved by the app or transmitted over the internet?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. The app saves no data except for basic preferences (window positioning &amp;amp; size etc.). There is never any data sent over the network and the app will work perfectly if you disconnect your computer before using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are those 3 buttons: #, A and 1?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some sites may require a passphrase that contains a mix of character types. These buttons will insert a special character, change the start of one word to uppercase, or insert a number. Tap the button again to undo the change. Again, these characters are chosen using the dice roll system and the special characters are selected and positioned using the method and data suggested by Arnold Reinhold.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/dicepass/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/dicepass/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Watch First Impressions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I realise that every one has written one of these posts, but given that everyone looks for and notices different things, I think it is still valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first impression was “Why does it come in such a large box?”. The courier delivered two boxes - my 38mm Apple Watch Sport and Tim’s 42mm Apple Watch Sport. They both came in long boxes, with the 42mm box significantly longer. And both boxes were heavy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;un-boxing&quot;&gt;Un-boxing:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening them was a typical Apple experience: pull the tag to open the external cardboard box, lift out the white internal box. This opens to reveal the watch with the default strap attached (short for 38mm, long for 42mm). Lift the watch out and pull the tags to remove the plastic protective coating. (On a side note, it drives me crazy when people leave this coating on devices, but I can’t see this happening on the watch.) Underneath there is a sleeve containing the other half watch strap so you can swap from long to short. My family tells me that this also includes a user guide, but I didn’t read that - typical Apple user… Under the sleeve is the power block and charging cable. The charging puck is larger than I expected and the cable is very long. Having removed all the components, the packaging is still quite heavy, so I guess Apple just wanted to make sure that no watches were damaged in transit and that it felt like a quality product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pairing&quot;&gt;Pairing:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing my watch to my iPhone was amazingly slick. After selecting my language, the watch displayed a sort of nebula pattern. On the iPhone, I launched the Apple Watch app, selected the pairing option and pointed the phone camera at the watch display. This did the pairing. Then I waited while all the relevant apps transferred their Apple Watch components to the watch and I was ready to start using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-watch&quot;&gt;The Watch:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch comes with the modular watch face showing by default. This is a digital time read-out with various ‘complications’. 
Force-touch the watch face to change it - this takes a surprisingly strong touch. Then you can swipe sideways to select a watch style. Once you have a style selected, some of them offer further customisations: select how much detail is shown, choose what extra information to display, adjust colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a lot of fun and I am still changing mine very frequently. The good thing is that your customisations are stored, so if you set up the utility watch face in a particular way, then swap to the modular and configure it, when you go back to utility, your previous settings are all still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screen is gorgeous - very crisp and easy to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twisting your wrist to show the time works well most of the time. There is a delay that I would estimate at about half a second, presumably to avoid false positives triggering unnecessary displays. If you are holding your wrist at an unusual angle e.g. showing the watch to someone, this twist will not always work, but tapping the screen will display the watch face instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapping on a complication will take you to the relevant parent app e.g. tapping the current temperature will open the Weather app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A minor quibble is that the phases of the moon are displayed from a northern hemisphere point of view and do not match what we actually see here in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;battery-life&quot;&gt;Battery Life:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a complete non-issue. On my first day with the watch, the battery was at 70% when I first turned it on. As you can imagine, usage was very intense that first day and I got to 8%. Since then, the battery level has only got down to 40 -50% over a day and it recharges to 100% within 2 hours. Tim’s 42mm model gets slightly better battery life as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off having the battery indicator as one of the ‘complications’ on my watch face, but now I just ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the battery life of my iPhone has improved remarkably due to so many quick transactions being done through the watch instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have a charging problem one night. I woke up and checked the time and realised that the watch was quite warm to the touch. I checked the battery level which was actually lower than when I had put it on the charger. I took it off the charger for a few hours, then put it back and all was well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;notifications&quot;&gt;Notifications:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is where you need to be careful. I had turned off most notifications on my phone before getting the watch, so I have not been inconvenienced, in fact I have been able to re-enable many notifications as they are no longer so intrusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first we thought some notifications were not getting through to the watch, then we found out that if your iPhone is awake and un-locked, notifications are not passed on to the watch. So drop the time until sleep on your phone to the minimum which saves your phone battery and makes sure you receive most notifications on the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to stop any apps sending notifications through to the watch, this is easily set in the iPhone’s Apple Watch app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have noticed there is a bit of a delay. I hear an email or message arriving on my phone and it can be half a minute before it gets to my watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get a notification, you can tap it to go to the parent app, swipe up to process it in some way depending on the type of notification, or swipe to the left to see a button that will clear the notification. If you want to get rid of all your notifications at once, do a force-touch on the notifications screen to get the option to clear them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;glances&quot;&gt;Glances:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glances are designed to be one screen indicators giving you important information as quickly as possible. From there, you can decide whether to go to the parent app or not. These are accessed by swiping up from the bottom of the screen when looking at the watch face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the most important thing here was to reduce the number of glances shown, since they are displayed sequentially. If you have 20 glances installed, you have to swipe at least 20 times to see them all. So go to the Apple Watch app on your iPhone and turn off the glances you do not find essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first glance in the sequence is essential though as it allows you to toggle airplane mode, do not disturb and silent mode. It also has a button that can make your iPhone make a sound to help you locate it. Hold this button down to make the iPhone flash come on as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;activity&quot;&gt;Activity:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I have to confess to my first disappointment. The activity app tracks three things: Move, Exercise and Stand. When you first start the watch, you tell it your age, sex, weight and height. It computes a suggested daily move goal for you which you can adjust at any time. Then it tracks your daily activities and shows how well you are doing in relation to your goal. For exercise and standing the goals are 30 minutes exercise and standing for at least one minute in an hour 12 times though the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move tracking seems to be fine. I am not sure what metrics it uses, but on more active days, the numbers go up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exercise one doesn’t work for me. We went for a walk and when we returned, Tim’s watch showed 25 minutes exercise and mine showed 1 minute. We had walked the same distance at the same speed, as confirmed by the pedometer. Subsequent tests revealed that I don’t swing my arms enough when walking to trigger what ever sensor this is using. I can’t quite see why it ignores the pedometer completely, but hopefully this can be fixed by a software update. For now, I just ignore this circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing is another issue since I use a standing desk, so I stand for many hours each day. Even when standing, I get my hourly reminders to stand. However I use this as a trigger to make me to move about for a minute, so I suppose that is still useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;communications&quot;&gt;Communications:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The various forms of communication are a real strength of the watch. With Tim &amp;amp; I both having watches, we can phone, message (audio or text) and use the new Digital Touch to send sketches, taps or heart beats. While it feels a bit weird to be talking to your wrist, this works really well and the sound quality is amazing for such a small device. If you need more privacy, it is very easy to transfer a phone call back to your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly, the watch does not appear to offer FaceTime but always uses standard phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messages are where the watch excels. If you get a message with a question, the watch can suggest possible answers so you just have to tap a button. Even without this, there is a set of pre-defined answers which you can edit in the Apple Watch app on your iPhone. And you can also use dictation or the new animated emojis. Dictation seems a lot better on the watch than it ever was before on the phone. And even if dictation is not transcribed perfectly, you can send the message as an audio recording instead of text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When recording, tap the Done button as soon as you have finished speaking. The inclination is to wait for the text to be processed, but the recording carries on, so stop the recording and let the text processing finish in its own time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animated emojis work when you send them to other devices as they appear as GIFs. You can choose from 3 sets: faces, hands and hearts. Once you have swiped to select a set, use the crown to scroll between the options. You can also swipe further to get to the standard emojis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Touch works between watches only. It is a fun gimmick and I can imagine us developing a set of key codes or sketches, but neither of us can draw very well, so the sketches are very rough. The heart beat is amusing, but the tapping is surprisingly effective as an attention-getter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is the start of a new way of interacting with our technology in a way that is both closer to us and less intrusive. I am loving the watch so far and can’t wait to see where it goes from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2015/04/apple-watch-first-impressions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2015/04/apple-watch-first-impressions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time In Words 4.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/time-in-words/&quot;&gt;Time In Words&lt;/a&gt; for iOS started off as a fun gimmick, emulating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qlocktwo.com/&quot;&gt;Qlocktwo&lt;/a&gt; type of time display where the relevant words are highlighted in some way to spell out the time as a sentence. This very quickly evolved into what I hoped would be more useful app, still showing the original display, but also providing the current time &amp;amp; date as complete sentences. Then I added time conversions and discovered the real power and utility of writing out times as words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to converting times, I doubt there are many people in the world who haven’t had problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is that morning or afternoon for them?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they in tomorrow, today or yesterday?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if they are using daylight-savings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the time written out removes all ambiguity.
As an example, Time In Words currently reports very clearly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Los Angeles, it is nine minutes to ten on Tuesday evening (daylight-savings time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing &lt;a href=&quot;/time-in-words-for-mac/&quot;&gt;Time In Words for Mac&lt;/a&gt;, I focussed immediately on the time zone conversion facilities, and provided a menu bar app that can display as many time zones as you like (although more than will show on a single screen would probably get annoying).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I decided to do a complete re-write of Time In Words for iOS, the obvious move was to emulate the Mac version and allow for as many time zones as the user wants, instead of the current 2 or 4 (iPhone or iPad). So I discarded the Qlocktwo display and the separate date display which used a similar mechanic. I kept the display that shows the current date and time, but every display after that shows the time in a different time zone. The time zones can be changed and re-ordered, so the ones you need most are the fastest to get to once the app opens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One new feature (again taken from the Mac version), is the ability to calculate “What time will it be…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TiW_what_time.png&quot; alt=&quot;What time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You dial in your local date and time to see what time that will be in your selected zone. And if you want to calculate the other way around, tap the “Swap time zones” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main impetus for a re-write was the Apple Watch. I thought this would be a perfect app for the watch as it could use the Apple Watch’s superb time-keeping in conjunction with my text generation, to add a significant level of usability to the Apple Watch as regards time zone conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, Apple disagrees…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed the app and submitted it to the App Store for review. The review process seems to be very fast at the moment and the app moved into review only one day later. And there it stuck for 3 days. This was very odd. My experience is that once an app gets into review, it only takes a few hours, if that. For &lt;a href=&quot;/19th-hole/&quot;&gt;19th Hole&lt;/a&gt; - my other app with an Apple Watch component, the review process took 30 hours. But 3 days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got a phone call from Apple where a very polite person explained to me that although this was not mentioned in any of the documentation, the marketing people had decided that no apps were to be allowed on the watch if they told the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I offered to remove the initial screen telling the local time, so the app would not actually supply the current time but only the time conversions, but that was not acceptable either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I tried appealing the rejection. My hopes were not high, but I didn’t see any harm in asking. I again offered to remove the local time display and emphasised the accessibility advantages of displaying times in this manner. Another day, another phone call, another polite Apple person saying no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have re-submitted the app for review without the Apple Watch component, which is a shame. I am hoping that after some months they will review this policy and allow me to try again, but who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you can see what you are missing, here are a couple of screen shots from the watch app showing my local time, plus one time zone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Watch_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Local time&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;float_right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Watch_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Converted time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more minor point. People who actually look at version numbers may wonder why I have gone from version 2.5 to version 4.0. When I was working on version 2.5, I considered making it version 3.0 and then changed my mind. However by that time I had already created a version 3.0 in iTunesConnect, so I was not able to use 3.0 again this time. This version was such a big change that I wanted it to be a .0 release, so that meant going to version 4.0&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://troz.net/2015/04/time-in-words-4.0/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://troz.net/2015/04/time-in-words-4.0/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
