<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dice on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/dice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dice on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/dice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<title>Dice Pass Updated</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-updated/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-updated/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/dicepass/&#34;&gt;Dice Pass 1.1&lt;/a&gt; is now available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id997688302&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-dice-pass-do&#34;&gt;What does Dice Pass do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is a utility to app to generate random passphrases based on the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/diceware.html&#34;&gt;Diceware&lt;/a&gt; system. Diceware uses a table of pre-defined words, each assigned
a 5 digit code number containing the digits 1 to 6. The official way to generate
a phrase is to roll 5 dice for each word you want in your passphrase and then
consult the words table to find the matching word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting phrase uses real words or common abbreviations so it is easier to
remember than a random collection of characters. At the same time, the random
selection of words makes the generated passphrase much more secure as it avoids
the human tendency to pick words with personal meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass allows you to select the number of words in your passphrase,
re-generate the entire passphrase any time, re-roll a single word in your
passphrase or set the dice rolls manually for maximum security and randomness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-new-in-version-1-1&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in Version 1.1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now select from three word lists in the Word Lists menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;original Diceware list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beale list (fewer Americanisms and obscure words)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diceware 8k list (a list of words that is a whole power of two in length)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also import your own word list if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass 1.1 is compatible with macOS Sierra.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Dice Pass Mac Update</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-mac-update/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/dice-pass-mac-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got an email from someone who had purchased &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/dicepass/&#34;&gt;Dice Pass&lt;/a&gt; for Mac
from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id997688302&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt; but had been unable to get it to run. This person
was using OS X 10.9.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked the App Store specifications and it showed that 10.9 was the minimum
system requirement, so it should have worked. But going back to my Xcode
project, I found that it was set to a minimum of OS X 10.10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to re-compile for OS X 10.9 but this failed as the app uses several
features that are not available prior to 10.10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minimum system version as displayed in the App Store is supposedly deduced
automatically by the App Store servers from the app&amp;rsquo;s binary. Somehow this was
incorrect in the App Store, so some people may have bought that app and found
that it did not work despite them having what was listed as a compatible system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you bought Dice Pass for OS X 10.9 and are unable to run it, I have two
possible solutions for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade your operating system to at least 10.10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask Apple for a refund since it was their error that caused you to buy an app
that you cannot run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have updated the app in the App Store changing nothing but the version number
and it is now showing the correct minimum system requirement. My apologies if
you have been inconvenienced by this error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Dice Pass for Mac</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2015/dice-pass-for-mac/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/dice-pass-for-mac/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a world of passwords and passphrases and there is a constant struggle
between having a secure and a memorable password. As a result, many of us re-use
passwords even though we know this is a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/936/&#34;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; had a wonderful comic that illustrated the theory of using a
passphrase composed of words that are easy to remember but with a combination
that made the passphrase very hard to guess. However even when deciding to use a
passphrase like this, it is not easy for us humans to avoid using words that
have meaning for us, particularly when it is something we really need to
remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://world.std.com/~reinhold/diceware.html&#34;&gt;Diceware&lt;/a&gt; was developed to solve this problem. You have a set of 5 dice and
a list of words assigned to each possible dice roll for 11111 to 66666. You roll
the five dice and get the matching word from the list. Repeat this for the
number of words you want to use in your passphrase and you have a random phrase
that is hopefully still memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this sounds like a lot of effort and not something you are likely to do when
faced by a password entry field on a web page. So &lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/dicepass/&#34;&gt;Dice Pass&lt;/a&gt; was written to
do the work for you quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troz.net/images/DicePass_Mac.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dice Pass for Mac&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the number of words you want in your passphrase and see the phrase
immediately. Keep clicking the &amp;ldquo;Generate New Phrase&amp;rdquo; button until you get a
phrase you like. If you feel that the computer is not to be trusted when
generating a random number for the dice rolls, use your real dice and click the
dice to change them to the roll you got. If you get a passphrase that is good
except for one or two words, use the Re-Roll button beside those words to get a
new roll for just that word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice Pass is available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/dice-pass/id997688302?mt=12&amp;amp;uo=4&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>