<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ios on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ios on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasting</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2016/10/podcasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2016/10/podcasting/</guid>
      <description>I have recently started what I hope will be a weekly podcast with my friend and colleague, Jerry Daniels. Each podcast will be about 30 minutes in length.
We will discuss Macs, iPhones, iPads, macOS, iOS, programming and anything tech-related that we find interesting. I hope you will find it entertaining and informative, so please join us.
We are using ZCast which has an iPhone app that makes it super easy to get together and record our chats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring old apps</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2016/09/retiring-old-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2016/09/retiring-old-apps/</guid>
      <description>With the release of iOS 10 and the need to update iOS apps to suit, I have decided it is time to retire some of my lesser-performing apps as it is not worth the effort required to maintain them.
At the moment, the following iOS apps are no longer available:
 A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move Dice Pass Pic-a-POD Quick Score - Tennis  For the first three listed there, the Mac versions are still available:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19th Hole Golf Scorer 3.1</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2016/05/19th-hole-golf-scorer-3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2016/05/19th-hole-golf-scorer-3.1/</guid>
      <description>One of the problems with using 19th Hole on the Apple Watch is making the app show every time you raise your wrist. My solution to this was to go into Settings (either on my iPhone through the Watch app, or directly on the watch) and change it to &amp;ldquo;Resume Last Activity&amp;rdquo; on wrist raise. This worked fine but as I usually prefer the watch face to show on wrist raise, I had to keep setting and re-setting this which was a pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is My Speed?</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/what-is-my-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/what-is-my-speed/</guid>
      <description>img { display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto }  &amp;ldquo;What Is My Speed?&amp;rdquo; is available now from the iTunes App Store for iPhone and Apple Watch.
If you read my recent blog post on Road Trip Apps you will have realised that I was working on an app to fill a gap that I discovered in our road trip app arsenal. So here it is: &amp;ldquo;What Is My Speed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip Apps</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2016/04/road-trip-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2016/04/road-trip-apps/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, we have done two long road trips: one approximately 4,000 km and the other about 1,800 km. These gave us the chance to try out various apps for navigation and travel information. We live in Queensland, Australia and some of these comments may be country-specific.
Navigation The basic navigation came down to three apps:
 Apple Maps Google Maps Metroview (Australia and New Zealand only)  Each has their strengths and weaknesses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Builder 3.2 Released</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2016/02/icon-builder-32-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2016/02/icon-builder-32-released/</guid>
      <description>Icon Builder 3.2 is now available from the Mac App Store.
 Icons for Apple Watch apps now have their alpha channel removed. Tidier folder structure for related files (iTunes Artwork files and Read Me). Updated to work with Xcode 7&amp;rsquo;s Assets.xcassets folders. Creates iPad Pro icons for Xcode 7.2 or later. Fix for Retina Macs creating double-sized images.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2015/04/apple-watch-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2015/04/apple-watch-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I realise that every one has written one of these posts, but given that everyone looks for and notices different things, I think it is still valid.
My first impression was &amp;ldquo;Why does it come in such a large box?&amp;rdquo;. The courier delivered two boxes - my 38mm Apple Watch Sport and Tim&amp;rsquo;s 42mm Apple Watch Sport. They both came in long boxes, with the 42mm box significantly longer. And both boxes were heavy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words 4.0</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2015/04/time-in-words-4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2015/04/time-in-words-4.0/</guid>
      <description>Time In Words for iOS started off as a fun gimmick, emulating the Qlocktwo type of time display where the relevant words are highlighted in some way to spell out the time as a sentence. This very quickly evolved into what I hoped would be more useful app, still showing the original display, but also providing the current time &amp;amp; date as complete sentences. Then I added time conversions and discovered the real power and utility of writing out times as words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Apple Watch App</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2015/04/my-first-apple-watch-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2015/04/my-first-apple-watch-app/</guid>
      <description>I have just submitted my first Apple Watch app to the iTunes App Store. This is a scary thing to do, since I have never seen, touched or used an Apple Watch and all I had to go on was the Simulator that Apple supplies with Xcode.
At the moment, Apple has only made a limited set of Apple Watch features available to developers, and all Apple Watch apps come tethered to an iOS app - presumably this will mainly be iPhone apps, but I wonder will we be able to connect Apple Watches to iPads?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Builder 3.0.1</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2015/03/icon-builder-3.0.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2015/03/icon-builder-3.0.1/</guid>
      <description>So why an announcement for such a minor upgrade?
Version 3.0 got no announcement because it was not the release I wanted.
Having downloaded the Xcode 6.2 &amp;amp; 6.3 betas, I had worked out what icons were needed to a WatchKit app. This, combined with several other changes, made me bump the version number to 3.0.
Sadly, Apple rejected the update because it referred to pre-release products. So I pulled all mentions of WatchKit out of the interface and meta data and got 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19th Hole</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/19th-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/19th-hole/</guid>
      <description>19th Hole is the golf scoring app for everyone, and it is available from the iTunes App Store.
Whether you are playing for the club championship, having a weekend round with friends or playing pitch&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;putt with the kids, 19th Hole makes it easy to keep score.
Designed for fast, accurate score keeping with a color scheme chosen for optimal outdoor viewing, 19th Hole uses a simple setup process and an intuitive, gesture-based score entry system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Store Preview Videos</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/2015/03/app-store-preview-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/2015/03/app-store-preview-videos/</guid>
      <description>Apple now allows app developers to add a video preview of their app when uploading to iTunes Connect. This video is shown to potential purchasers when they are looking at an app in the iTunes App Store, just like the screen shots.
I have been working on an update to 19th Hole and since it uses a custom method for data input, I decided that a video would be really useful in this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email clients for Mac and iOS</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/email-clients-for-mac-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/email-clients-for-mac-ios/</guid>
      <description>Some people are moving away from email, but for me, it remains the best way to communicate online. I get to keep a record of conversations and the attached files are with the text so I can always see the context.
But I think everyone would agree that Apple have dropped the ball with Mail in OS X Mavericks, and to a lesser extent, in iOS 7.
So I have been on a campaign lately to find an email client that suits my needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berio Sequenza VII</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/berio-sequenza-vii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/berio-sequenza-vii/</guid>
      <description>So my latest app is way outside my usual sphere but that&amp;rsquo;s what happens when family decide that what you do might actually be useful!
My son is an oboist and he is currently learning Berio&amp;rsquo;s Sequenza VII for Oboe. This is a weird piece without a standard time signature. Instead each line has 13 bars with each bar being allocated a certain time span in actual seconds. As can easily be imagined, this makes learning and practicing this piece more of a mathematical exercise than a musical one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berio&#39;s Sequenza VII</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/berio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/berio/</guid>
      <description>Luciano Berio wrote a series of Sequenzas for various instruments with Sequenza VII being the one for oboe.
Preparing this work creates some unique problems for the oboist as Berio did not adhere to any time signature that could be indicated by a metronome. Instead, each line consists of 13 bars (measures) with each bar&amp;rsquo;s length specified in exact seconds.
When my son (an oboist currently studying in Melbourne, Australia) started trying to learn this piece, it occurred to him that having an iOS app developer in the family could be of some assistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Builder &amp; iOS 7</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-builder-ios-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-builder-ios-7/</guid>
      <description>Icon Builder 1.2 was released on 18 September 2013.
It was an update with 2 new functions:
 The ability to create images to suit an Xcode 5 assets library The ability to create icons with the required sizes for IOS 7 apps.  Knowing that iOS 7 apps can only be built using Xcode 5, I linked the switch for these 2 abilities in a single check box.
The problem was not really that they were in a single checkbox but that I had labelled it badly, so it was not obvious that this was what needed to be checked to create iOS 7 sized icon files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon apps updated</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-apps-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-apps-updated/</guid>
      <description>Icns Maker and Icon Builder have both just been updated to support Xcode 5.
Icon Builder is a Mac app that takes your images and creates all the required icon files for use in your iOS apps.
It now supports Xcode 5&amp;rsquo;s image assets folders and if you are using Xcode 5, it will create the icon sizes required for iOS 7 app.
Icns Maker is a Mac app that takes your images and creates icons for use in your Mac apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Makers &amp; Retina Macs</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-makers-retina-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-makers-retina-macs/</guid>
      <description>Icns Maker which makes an icns icon file for Mac apps, and Icon Builder which makes the suite of png files needed for iOS apps, are both compatible with the Retina MacBook Pro.
However it was recently brought to my attention (thanks Cameron), that when running on a Retina MBP, all the icon files were exactly twice as large as they should be. The Icon.png file which supplies the main app icon for iPhone apps should be 57 pixels by 57 pixels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Store Review Times</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/app-store-review-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/app-store-review-times/</guid>
      <description>There are been a lots of stories going around about lengthening Mac App Store review times. Shiny Developments crowd-sourced data certainly backs this up although they have much more data for iOS apps than for Mac apps.
Some people, including Lex Friedman of MacWorld and John Gruber of Daring Fireball, are suggesting that the delays are due to the rush of new apps to support the iPhone 5 and iOS 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon makers for Mac &amp; iOS apps</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-makers-for-mac-ios-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-makers-for-mac-ios-apps/</guid>
      <description>Announcing two new apps for creating icons for with Mac or iOS projects:
Icns Maker helps you convert a single image into a .icns file in two steps.
Icon Builder creates all the files needed to set up your icons for any iOS project.
Creating icon files for Mac apps: In versions of Xcode before 4.4, Apple provided an app called “Icon Composer”. It allowed you to drag images into a window and export a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icon Builder</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/icon-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/icon-builder/</guid>
      <description>Icon Builder 3.2 is available from the Mac App Store.
Make and install a set of icons for an iOS, Mac or Apple Watch app in 3 steps: 1: Drag an image into the window.
2: Choose the device family you are building for: iOS Universal, iPhone, iPad, Mac or Apple Watch.
If you are building for iOS and your app still supports iOS 6, then you need to change the setting in the iOS popup menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating apps for iPhone 5</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/updating-apps-for-iphone-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/updating-apps-for-iphone-5/</guid>
      <description>I have started work updating my iOS apps to fill the larger screen of an iPhone 5. My iPhone 5 is on order - I missed out on the first shipment, but hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be too long. Meanwhile, I will just test in the iPhone Simulator and hope this is OK.
But it was a puzzle to me how to get an app to fill the longer screen. I have the latest Xcode and the latest Simulator which allows you to specify what screen size iPhone to simulate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words &amp; the new iPad</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words-the-new-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words-the-new-ipad/</guid>
      <description>The new iPad has a Retina display, meaning that the pixel density is much greater. For some apps, this is a problem as their graphics are now scaled and look pixellated. However Time In Words is very simple. It uses standard fonts and interface widgets with no images or external graphics apart from the icon. The icon may not look perfect on a new iPad, but the display itself should look really great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words available in the App Store</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words-available-in-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words-available-in-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>Time In Words is now available at the App Store.
Time In Words is a clock and calendar app that takes you out of the digital era and back to when saying “quarter to seven” or “five past two” was accurate enough.

Check out the Time In Words web page for more info and screen shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time In Words for iOS</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/time-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/time-in-words/</guid>
      <description>Time In Words is a clock and calendar app that takes you out of the digital era and back to when saying &amp;ldquo;quarter to seven&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;five past two&amp;rdquo; was accurate enough. When people look at an analog watch, they tend to interpret the time to the closest five minutes which allows for inaccuracies in the watch as well as providing only a useful level of detail. This app goes back to that, showing date and/or time in multiple ways, but all in words.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>