<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chess on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/chess/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chess on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/chess/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Knight&#39;s Move 1.3</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/a-knights-move-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/a-knights-move-1-3/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: September 2016 - A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move for iOS is no longer available.
A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move for Mac is still supported.
A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move has been updated to version 1.3. The Mac version is available through the Mac App Store.
Three new level packs:  Eight by Eight Bishops Rule Castles  Eight by Eight has every puzzle set in a chessboard sized grid with more conventional placing of pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Knight&#39;s Move Released</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/a-knights-move-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/a-knights-move-released/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: September 2016 - A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move for iOS is no longer available.
A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move for Mac is still supported.
&amp;ldquo;A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move&amp;rdquo; is a fun, addictive and simple puzzle game based on the movements of chess pieces. Your goal is to move your white knight across a board to a target square using the same movements as a knight in chess. Pawns may block your way, while enemy bishops, castles, knights and the queen may try to stop you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Knight&#39;s Move</title>
      <link>https://troz.net/knightsmove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/knightsmove/</guid>
      <description>A Knight&amp;rsquo;s Move is a puzzle game where you have to move your knight across a board to a target square using the same movements as a knight in chess. Pawns may block your way, while enemy bishops, castles, knights and the queen may try to stop you.
UPDATE: Version 1.3 for Mac now available.
 Available from the Mac App Store for OS X 10.7 or later  Get from the starting position to the target in the shortest possible number of moves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>