<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xcode on TrozWare</title>
    <link>https://troz.net/tags/xcode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xcode on TrozWare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>© 2012 - 2019 Sarah Reichelt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://troz.net/tags/xcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<title>How To Confuse TestFlight</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/how-to-confuse-testflight/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/how-to-confuse-testflight/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into an unusual problem when testing my latest app: &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/what-is-my-speed/&#34;&gt;What Is My
Speed?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. It is now available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/what-is-my-speed/id1091394524&#34;&gt;iTunes App Store&lt;/a&gt;, but getting
there was a struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xcode is terrible at renaming projects, so it is a really good idea to have
worked out your app&amp;rsquo;s name before starting. I would even recommend creating an
app ID in your Apple Developer account and registering the app name in iTunes
Connect. Only once you get to iTunes Connect will the name be checked for
uniqueness. Searching the App Stores is not enough as it does not cover
un-released apps or apps that are not available in your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set up my app. I was hoping for &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s My Speed?&amp;rdquo; but was happy with &amp;ldquo;What
Is My Speed?&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step was to create the project in Xcode which I did using the app name and
manually entering the bundle identifier that I had registered at Apple
Developer. Xcode accepted the name without any warnings and created the default
targets using that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the default unit testing file, the module was defined like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34; data-lang=&#34;swift&#34;&gt; @testable &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;What&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Is_My_Speed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which made me think that Xcode was quite happy to have parsed the app name as
required to replace any unwanted characters to suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app was built, passed all unit tests, profiled, analyzed, tested on real
devices as well as the simulators and uploaded to TestFlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BARRRPPPP!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troz.net/images/TestFlight_error.png&#34; alt=&#34;This app cannot be installed&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I forgot to take a screenshot but found a similar one online. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.simpletechs.net/apps/easy-fix-for-testflight-problem-after-restoring-from-backup/&#34;&gt;Simple
Techs&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had experience with TestFlight&amp;rsquo;s oddities in the past, so I incremented
the build number and tried again, thinking that maybe there had been a
processing issue. Same result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This started a very frustrating 24 hours as I ran through all the possibilities
I could think of or find suggested on the net. Due to disastrous Australian
internet speeds, especially uploads, each attempt took from 40 - 120 minutes.
About 5 minutes to implement the next idea, 25 minutes upload time, then the
rest waiting for Apple to process the app so I could try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I tried:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploaded a fresh build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed Bitcode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the code signing identity which was set to iOS Developer for some
reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually specified the provisioning profiles for all three components (iPhone
app, WatchKit app, WatchKit Extension).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually selected the code signing identity for the provisioning profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploaded using Application Loader instead of Xcode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed third-party framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed WatchKit app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revoked my distribution profile, re-created it and updated all provisioning
profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a completely blank project with same app name and bundle identifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from this list, I thought it was a code signing or profile error.
Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/apple-configurator-2/id1037126344&#34;&gt;Apple Configurator 2&lt;/a&gt; (the modern version of iPhone Configuration
Utility), I was able to get the logs from my iPhone and entries like the
following seemed to confirm this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Error&#34;&gt;installd.staging/temp.2LWJ2h/extracted/Payload/What Is My Speed?.app : 0xe8008017 (A signed resource has been added, modified, or deleted.)}```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I got to the stage of a completely blank app still failing, I suddenly
thought of the question mark. With the benefit of my preamble to this post, you
all probably got there long before I did, but I got there in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution was to remove the question mark from the names of the targets in
Xcode. I had to fix up the module names in my unit testing files, but apart from
that, there were no changes. After this I was able to upload the complete app to
TestFlight and install it on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible that it was the Product Names that were the issue, rather than
the target name as in Build Settings, Product Name is set to be &lt;code&gt;$(TARGET_NAME)&lt;/code&gt;
by default but I didn&amp;rsquo;t test that. Maybe next time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/a&gt; Do not put any unusual characters in your target names.
Alphanumerics and spaces are OK, but I am not sure about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Configuring Xcode</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/configuring-xcode/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/configuring-xcode/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;While not strictly a part of my Learning Swift series, today I thought I would
discuss some of the ways to configure and use Xcode to be a more productive and
comfortable programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-editor-color-themes-and-fonts&#34;&gt;1. Editor color themes and fonts:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troz.net/images/XcodeFontPrefs.png&#34; alt=&#34;Editor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step through the supplied themes and find the best one for you. Then click the
&amp;lsquo;+&amp;rsquo; button at the bottom of the list and duplicate the selected theme. Now you
can tweak it to suit you. Each text category can have its own font and size, but
you can make multiple selections in order to do a bulk change. don&amp;rsquo;t forget to
check out the Console section too - I dislike the default bold text for many of
the console reports, so always change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An editing font should be mono-spaced i.e. every character should take up
exactly the same width on the screen. This makes your code look neater and
neater code is easier to read when you come back to it. I also much prefer a
sans-serif font, but that is a matter of preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Menlo is the font used by Xcode as a default, but there are many other options
either in the default installation of OS X or as free downloads. I change every
now and then just to keep things interesting, but my current selection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonsky/FiraCode&#34;&gt;Fira
Code&lt;/a&gt;. I love the way it merges two character symbols into a single
character for faster comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other favourites are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adobe-fonts/source-code-pro&#34;&gt;Source Code Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chrissimpkins/hack&#34;&gt;Hack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mozilla/Fira&#34;&gt;Fira&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fontsquirrel.com/fonts/Inconsolata&#34;&gt;Inconsolata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for a font that makes it easy to distinguish the digit &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; from a lowercase
&amp;lsquo;l&amp;rsquo; and where the digit &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo; is different to the &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install and use a new font, download the files and then double-click a TTF or
OTF font file to install it in FontBook. Once the font is installed, you may
need to restart Xcode in order to make it available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-add-ons&#34;&gt;2. Add-ons:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Xcode 8 has removed the ability to run any plugins or to use
Alcatraz, so this sectrion is no longer valid. Instead Apple is offering offical
support for Xcode Source Editor Extensions, so they are the way of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-documentation&#34;&gt;3. Documentation:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xcode has excellent documentation, but unless you specifically download it, this
will all be accessed online. If you have a bad or non-existent connection, this
can be annoying. Go to Xcode&amp;rsquo;s Preferences -&amp;gt; Downloads and download all the
document sets you are interested in. They are quite large, but having them local
will be a big bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other tool I use for documentation is &lt;a href=&#34;https://kapeli.com/dash&#34;&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt;. It supports many languages
and is not just for use in Xcode. I found the Xcode integration plugin was not
very useful as it conflicted with other useful behaviours. So I set up a global
shortcut in System Preferences to search Dash for the selected text. This is
much faster than Xcode&amp;rsquo;s built-in documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://troz.net/images/Dash.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dash&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-other-preferences&#34;&gt;4. Other preferences:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the preference panes in Xcode&amp;rsquo;s preferences and tweak to suit your
style or your group&amp;rsquo;s preferred style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General and Text Editing are important. Text Editing has a second tab for
Indentation which is easy to miss. Indentation styles seem to cause a lot of
heated debate, so make sure you check this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts is vital if you are publishing to the App Stores and also makes it easy
to transfer all your develop information from one computer to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fonts &amp;amp; Colors and Downloads are discussed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to leave the others set to the defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Possible issues with Icon Builder &amp; Watch icons</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2016/possible-issues-with-iconbuilder/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2016/possible-issues-with-iconbuilder/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that there are two possible issues with Icon Builder
3.0.1 when using icons created for an Apple Watch app. Once of them is something
I can fix and the other appears to be a bug in Xcode 7.2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Version 3.2 of Icon Builder is now available in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/icon-builder/id552293482&#34;&gt;Mac App
Store&lt;/a&gt;. This removes the alpha channel from icons for a watch app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first problem is that iTines Connect now requires that the icons for an
Apple Watch app include no alpha channel. This is becoming an increasing trend
with it first having applied to the large icon file you upload directly to
iTunes Connect, then to screen shots. I expect it to extend to iOS app icons
soon, but hopefully Mac app icons can continue to include transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Apple Watch icons, you are supposed to create a set of square icons and
watchOS or iTunesConnect applies the rounding mask. Presumably this is more
complicated if the icon contains an alpha channel even if there are no
transparent pixels. If your Watch app icons contain an alpha channel, you will
see errors like this after uploading your app to iTunes Connect:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invalid Icon - The watch application &amp;lsquo;AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit
App.app&amp;rsquo; contains an icon file &amp;lsquo;AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit
App.app/AppIcon-Watch24x24@2x.png&amp;rsquo; with an alpha channel. Icons should not
have an alpha channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will probably get this error message for every icon size in the Watch app (8
in total). Until I release a new version of Icon Builder that allows for this
this, I suggest you use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cocoacontrols.com/controls/alpha-channel-remover&#34;&gt;Alpha Channel Remover app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Xcode project, go to WatchKit App Assets.xcassets, select the AppIcon
set, right-click and choose &amp;ldquo;Show in Finder&amp;rdquo;. A folder will open containing
eight .png files and one .json file. Drag &amp;amp; drop the .png files into the Alpha
Channel Remover window and click the &amp;ldquo;Remove Alpha Channel&amp;rdquo; button. This will
replace all those image files with new versions without alpha channels. To
confirm this, select any of the images and press Command-I to get info. In the
More Info section, you will see &amp;ldquo;Alpha channel: No&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now submit your app again, but that only solves one of the issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that you will get a warning about the 44x44@2x.png icon
file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invalid Icon Name - The watch application &amp;lsquo;AppName.app/Watch/AppName WatchKit
App.app&amp;rsquo; contains an invalid icon file name &amp;lsquo;AppName.app/Watch/AppName
WatchKit App.app/AppIcon-Watch44x44@2x.png&amp;rsquo;. Make sure that icon file names
follow the pattern&lt;br&gt; &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;*&amp;lt;dimension&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;scale&amp;gt;x.png&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo; and they match the
required dimensions. Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/watchkit/&#34;&gt;https://developer.apple.com/watchkit/&lt;/a&gt; for
more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the error message, the icon name (which is set by Xcode) does
conform to the required pattern, and the image is the correct size. This appears
to be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openradar.me/23801324&#34;&gt;bug in Xcode 7.2&lt;/a&gt; but does not stop you from submitting your app as
it is only a warning and not an error. Presumably this will be fixed in later
version of Xcode. I am running Xcode 7.2.1 and still see this warning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
    <item>
<title>Icon Builder 3.0.1</title>
<link>https://troz.net/post/2015/icon-builder-3.0.1/</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troz.net/post/2015/icon-builder-3.0.1/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;So why an announcement for such a minor upgrade?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 3.0 got no announcement because it was not the release I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having downloaded the Xcode 6.2 &amp;amp; 6.3 betas, I had worked out what icons were
needed to a WatchKit app. This, combined with several other changes, made me
bump the version number to 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, Apple rejected the update because it referred to pre-release products. So
I pulled all mentions of WatchKit out of the interface and meta data and got 3.0
released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Apple keynote on March 9th, I re-enabled the WatchKit portions of the
app and re-submitted to the App Store, hoping that with the WatchKit SDK now
part of the official Xcode release, Apple&amp;rsquo;s reviewers would allow it to get
through this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked - in fact the app was reviewed and accepted within 6 days - so now
Icon Builder adds WatchKit to its list of supported platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, Apple may have done me a favour in rejecting the first one as they
changed the specifications for the icons slightly between Xcode 6.2 beta and
Xcode 6.2 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://troz.net/icon-builder/&#34;&gt;Icon Builder page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icon-builder/id552293482?mt=12&amp;amp;uo=4&#34;&gt;Mac App Store link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-new-in-version-3&#34;&gt;What’s New in version 3?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for WatchKit app icons (version 3.0.1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified interface: removed display of smaller icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix for @3x images not being saved when you selected iOS 6 support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunesArtwork@2x file now saved as a JPG to avoid iTunes Connect errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed CarPlay icon - Xcode sometimes gave errors when this was included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
</item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>